[Music]
[音乐]
53% of you are planning to make a New
53% 的人计划在今年新年制定
Year's resolution about money finance
关于金钱、理财
and investing this year because you want
和投资的计划，因为你们渴望
Financial Freedom and Financial Security
财务自由和财务安全。
so we went through every conversation
因此，我们回顾了所有
we've had about money personal finance
关于金钱、个人理财
and investing and we found the most
和投资的对话，并从中挑选出最常被
replayed and most shared moments from
提及和分享的精彩片段，
those conversations for you everything
供大家参考。这些内容涵盖了从
from life-changing advice on saving
储蓄、
spending investing tax crypto buying a
消费、投资、税务、加密货币、购房到
house and having a money mindset the
建立正确的金钱观等各个方面，能够改变人生的建议。
most expensive thing that all of us are
我们所有人付出的最大代价
paying for is the information that we
就是我们
don't know so how do you make the most
不知道的信息。那么，如何才能赚到
money humanly possible it's two things
尽可能多的钱呢？答案是两点。
let me tell you a few key basic things
让我来告诉你一些关于投资的关键基础知识，它们
about investing in money it's going to
将
lead to amount of success that will
带给你巨大的成功，让
literally put you in the top 5% of
你跻身前 5% 的
investors but never have to worry about
投资者之列，并且从此不再为
money again if you listen to this
金钱担忧。如果你听了这次
conversation we believe your money goals
对话，我们相信你的理财目标
will come true in 2025 so take
将在 2025 年实现。所以，记好
notes quick one before we get back to
笔记吧。在我们继续
this episode just give me 30 seconds of
本期节目之前，请给我 30 秒
your time two things I wanted to say the
时间，我想说两件事。
first thing is a huge thank you for
首先，非常感谢大家
listening and tuning into the show week
每周收听和收看我们的节目，
after week it means the well to all of
这对我们所有人来说意义非凡。 这
us and this really is a dream that we
真的是我们
absolutely never had and couldn't have
从未想过，也从未想过能
imagined getting to this place but
走到今天这一步的梦想。
secondly it's a dream where we feel like
其次，我们感觉
we're only just getting started and if
这仅仅是个开始。如果
you enjoy what we do here please join
您喜欢我们的节目，请加入
regularly and have hit the Subscribe
定期观看我们频道并点击订阅
button means more than I can say and if
按钮的24%的观众行列。您的支持对我意义非凡。如果
you hit that subscribe button here's a
您点击了订阅按钮，
promise I'm going to make to you I'm
我向您承诺：我会
going to do everything in my power to
竭尽全力
make this show as good as as I can now
让这个节目现在
and into the future we're going to
和未来都保持最佳状态。我们会
deliver the guests that you want me to
邀请您想让我采访的嘉宾，并
keep doing all of the things you love
继续做所有您喜欢这个
about the show thank you thank you so
节目的内容。非常感谢！
much back to the
回到正
episode so what is the S&amp;P 500 for
题。那么，对于不了解的人来说，什么是标普500指数？
from investing in the S&amp;P 500 I really
投资标普500指数的回报又是多少呢？我
want to simplify this for people that
想用最简单的方式解释给那些刚刚
are at the very start of their investing
开始投资的人听，
Journey you know because I mean this is
因为我知道，投资是
what you spend so much of your time
你们花费大量时间
doing that I just think about my my team
去做的事情，所以我会思考…… 我们团队
here say the dire of a CEO there's about
大概有
30 people and we started talking about
30个人，其中一位CEO是位资深人士。有一天我们开始聊
money one day and it was mindblowing how
钱，结果发现
nobody in my team's lives had ever had
团队成员竟然从来没有人
the conversation with them about
跟我们谈过
investing we all think of investing as
投资，这让我大吃一惊。我们都觉得投资是
of 40 do once you have a million dollars
40岁以后有钱人的事，等你有了100万美元才开始。
um Al if you don't have a million
嗯，如果你没有100万
dollars then the only other way to
美元，那么
invest we're taught is to buy a house ah
我们被教导的唯一投资方式就是买房。啊，
this is driving me insane it's true
这简直让我抓狂！
though isn't it yes and that's that's
不过，这确实是事实，不是吗？没错。而这正是
the central part of my work is that you
我工作的核心：你
can live a rich life and that rich life
可以过上富足的生活，而且这种富足的生活
can be richer and more vibrant and more
可以比你想象的更丰富、更精彩、更
personal than you ever imagined if you
个性化。如果你
want to travel you can travel for longer
想旅行，你可以旅行的时间
than you ever thought you can travel for
比你想象的更长；你可以入住
me at nicer hotels you can uh spend more
更好的酒店；你可以花更多的
time with your children with your loved
时间陪伴你的孩子和
ones whatever your rich life is you can
爱人。无论你想象中的富足生活是什么样的，你都可以
do that but you've got to learn a few
做到。但你必须学习一些
key basic things about investing and
关于投资和金钱的关键基础知识。
money so let me tell you what I would
所以，让我告诉你，
tell my family when they come to me they
当我的家人来问我“
go how should I start investing the
我应该如何开始投资”时，我会怎么回答他们。
simplest simplest way that I advise my
我给家人建议的最简单方法
family is I say get a Target date fund
就是投资目标日期基金。
so let me explain what that is a target
让我解释一下什么是目标日期基金。目标
date fund is One Fund just one and you
日期基金就是一只基金，你
pick it based on the year that you're
根据你的退休年份来选择。比如，
going to retire so if you're going to
如果你计划
retire in
在
20150 if you're going to be 65 in 2050
2015年退休，那么如果你在2050年65岁，
you go and you find that one fund it's
你就去找一只这样的基金，比如
called a Vanguard 2065 fund or Fidelity
先锋2065基金、富达2065基金或者
2065 or Schwab 2065 there's lots of
嘉信理财2065基金等等，有很多
Brokers These funds it's One Fund all
券商都提供这类基金。
you do is put money into it that's it
你只需要把钱投进去就行了。这只
the fund like a pie chart is
基金就像一个饼图，会
automatically Diversified so as you get
自动分散投资。随着
older it gets more conservative because
年龄的增长，它的投资组合会变得更加保守，因为
somebody who's 75 years old should be
75岁的人和25岁的
investing differently than somebody
人应该采取不同的投资策略。
25 One Fund all you have to do is set
你只需要设置好
month what is a fund a fund is uh a a
每月定期投资，这只基金就足够了。那么什么是基金呢？基金就是一
set or a basket of stocks and maybe
篮子股票，也可能包含
bonds so we've all heard of you know
债券。我们都听说过
companies like Microsoft Google whatever
微软、谷歌之类的公司。
a fund owns lots of these right and
基金持有很多这类股票，
that's important because we've heard
这很重要，因为我们都听说过
diversification like you should have
分散投资，比如你应该
Diversified your Investments okay well
分散投资。那么，该
how do I do that you don't need to go
怎么做呢？你不需要自己
and buy 20 stocks and then figure out
去买20只股票，然后再去计算
how much of each to do that's too much
每只股票的持仓比例，那样太
work and honestly most people are not
麻烦了，而且说实话，大多数人都不
good at that even professionals you buy
擅长，即使是专业人士也不例外。你可以购买
a fund which automatically owns lots of
一只基金，它会自动持有
stocks like hundreds of them and over
数百只股票。随着
time all you the individual investor
时间的推移，
like me have to focus on is putting
像我这样的个人投资者只需要专注于
money into it automatically so a fund
自动往里面投钱。所以，
essentially I've got1 pounds that I want
假设我有1英镑想
to invest um I find a fund where do I
投资，那么我该去哪里找一只基金呢？
find these funds you can go to Vanguard
你可以去Vanguard、
Schwab or Fidelity all those are great
Schwab或Fidelity，这些都是很棒的
companies uh what looking for regardless
公司。无论
of what country you're in is you're
你在哪个国家，你都应该
looking for a lowcost brokerage firm so
寻找一家低成本的经纪公司。当然，
can you can use apps I don't like a lot
你也可以使用一些应用程序。我不喜欢很多
of the apps because they gamify you to
应用程序，因为它们会把
try to invest they want you clicking and
投资游戏化，让你不停地点击和
trading I hate Traders Trad you do not
交易。我讨厌交易员，你绝对不想
want to be a Trader Traders lose money
成为交易员。 交易员赔钱，
investors treat investing like watching
投资者把投资当成看
paint dry that's how sexy it is trust me
油漆干一样无聊，这就是投资的魅力所在。相信我，
investing I'm going out go watch a movie
投资可不是我的娱乐方式，我会出去看电影、
go watch
看
Netflix but investing is boring and
Netflix，但投资枯燥乏味，而且是
automatic that's how it should be I used
自动化的，这才是它应有的样子。我刚开始投资的时候，用过
a a a company called HRI lands down in
一家叫HRI的公司，
the UK who have an app when I first
他们有个app。
started investing um when I first
嗯，我刚
started investing in funds they they had
开始投资基金的时候，他们的
a very ugly app so I wasn't very
app很丑，所以我不太
compelled to use I think it's better now
想用。我觉得现在好多了，
but I would use just do it on desktop
但我还是会直接在电脑上操作。
which I do get your point because you
我明白你的意思，因为你
don't want to you don't want to be game
不想，你不想玩游戏，你不想
you don't want to screen all of that
盯着那些
notific like ug it should be ugly I you
通知看，呃，它本来就应该很丑。你
want it to be too accessible as in I
希望它太容易访问，比如，我
don't want to be able to check it every
不想每天都查看。
day no look on my phone you will see no
不，看看我的手机，你会发现没有
investing apps yes there should not be
投资app。是的，本来就不应该有。
why do you need to log in and check it
为什么要每天登录查看？有什么
every day what's the point yeah in fact
意义？是的，事实上，
I log you know what most people should
我登录过。你知道吗？大多数人应该
check it every three to six months and
每三到六个月查看一次。
here's how you check it you log in on
以下是查看方法： 在
your
你的
desktop wow it's up wow it's down okay
电脑上登录，哇，它又上线了，哇，它又关了。好吧，
bye you're not tweaking anything it's
再见。你什么都没做，就像
like making Thanksgiving dinner once
做感恩节晚餐一样，把
you've put the T in the oven just let it
火鸡放进烤箱后就让它
sit do not fiddle with it cuz you're
待着，不要动它，否则只会
only going to mess it up and in this
搞砸。在这种
case you're letting the turkey cook for
情况下，你要让火鸡烤几
decades and that fun so I've got 100
十年，这很有趣。所以我有100
pounds I go on a website Vanguard
英镑，我去了一个网站，Vanguard、
Fidelity Schwab whatever they are I have
Fidelity、Schwab，不管它们是什么，我跟
no Alliance to any of them neither do I
它们没有任何关系，我也没有。
um there's various ones in the UK I
嗯，英国有很多这样的公司。我
actually do recommend hgri land down
其实推荐Hgri Land Down，
just because it's simple and I think
因为它很简单，而且我认为
investing in funds there's no fees
投资基金没有费用，
investment itself obviously they take a
投资本身没有费用。当然，
you know they might take a percentage
他们会收取一定比例的费用，这
depending on which fund you're investing
取决于你投资的是哪个基金。
in I take
我拿出
my00 and investing in heve lands down
100英镑投资Hgri Land Down，
you don't need there's no um minimum
你不需要，没有最低投资额，太好了，据
great from what I understand and there's
我了解。
no if you invest in a stock they charge
如果你投资股票，他们
122 pounds per investment but if you
每笔投资收取122英镑，但如果你
invest in a fund it's free um I put
投资基金。 它是免费的。我把
my100 pounds into a fund the fund is
100英镑投进一个基金里。这个基金
essentially taking one pounds one of
本质上就是把这100英镑分成几份，
those pounds and investing one pound
一份投资
into Facebook it's investing one pound
Facebook，一份投资
into Google one pound into Shopify one
谷歌，一份投资Shopify，一份投资
pound into Spotify one pound into Nvidia
Spotify，一份投资Nvidia等等。它帮
or whatever it's doing that for me it's
我做这些，帮
managing it for me it's making the
我管理，帮
decisions for me I just put the money in
我做决定。我每个月都把钱投进去，尽
every month whatever I can and I leave
我所能，然后就不用管了。是的，我们再深入探讨一下。
it yeah and let's go even deeper I love
我很高兴
that we're getting into the nuts and
我们能深入了解
bolts here because you know honestly
其中的细节，因为你知道，说实话，
most people they do not know how to
大多数人根本不知道怎么投资。他们不知道该去哪个
invest literally what website do I go to
网站，也不知道该怎么做。这个
do the fund owns these different stocks
基金持有不同的股票，
and some will go up and some will go
有些会涨，有些会
down and it's inconsequential to you all
跌，但这对你来说无关紧要。
you need to know is you own this
你只需要知道你现在拥有这个
fund now that you've opened up an
基金。既然你已经
account and you've sent a hundred bucks
开户并存入了100英镑
or 1,000 bucks great you've made one of
或1000英镑，那就太好了，你已经做出了人生
the most important decisions of your
中最重要的决定之一。
life now there's just one more thing you
现在你只需要做最后一件事：
have to do set up an automatic transfer
设置自动转账。
so that every single month you have a
每个月你都会有一笔
certain amount of money going in now if
钱存进去。如果
you don't know how much money use my
你不知道该存多少钱，那就参考我的“
conscious spending plan guideline what
理性消费计划指南”。
did I say 5 to 10% of takehome is a good
我说过吗？税后收入的5%到10%是个不错的参考
guideline all right you should be able
标准。好吧，你应该能
to do 5% trust me anyone who comes to me
做到5%。相信我，每个来找我的人都会说：“
they go there's no way must be nice I
不可能，你人真好，我
can't afford I go show me where you're
负担不起。” 去告诉我你
spending your money I guarantee you I
的钱都花在哪儿了，我保证
can find 5% to send in every month now
每个月都能帮你找到5%存进去。现在
you're not trying to send it in I don't
你不用刻意去存钱，就像你不用刻意去刷牙一样，
it's a habit investing is even easier
这是一种习惯。投资比刷牙还容易，
than brushing your teeth because you set
因为你可以设置
it up automatically the investment fund
自动扣款。投资基金会
will automatically draw from your
自动从你的
checking account and it will pull in a
支票账户里扣款，扣款金额可以
your number is and so so you're not
是100美元、500美元、1000美元，或者你设定的任何金额。所以，你可能
going to log in for 3 four 5 months
三四个月甚至五个月都不用登录账户，
you're going to log in a few months
几个月
later you're going to be like oh my god
后你登录的时候就会惊呼：“我的天哪，我都没
I didn't even realize that all this
注意到账户里多了这么多
money is in here when you add that plus
钱！” 加上
compounding over many years that is how
多年的复利，这才是
real wealth is created so I don't want
真正财富的创造方式。所以我不想让
anyone to think that you have to be rich
任何人觉得你必须富有
in order to start investing one of the
才能开始投资。
ways you get rich is by investing I've
致富的方法之一就是投资。我
got a friend that's currently actually
有个朋友现在就
in this building at the moment and I had
在这栋楼里，
this conversation with them about a year
大约一年前我和他聊过这件事，
ago gave the advice that you've just
给了他你刚才
given there and about 2 months later
提到的建议。大约两个月后，
this individual who I Shan name came to
这个人（我叫他）来找
me and I said How's your uh you know
我，我问他：“你的
your your your Investments going in that
投资怎么样？你投到
in that fund and they said oh yeah I had
那个基金里的钱怎么样？” 他说：“哦，对，我有一些
bills I had a credit card bill so I I
账单要付，比如信用卡账单，所以我就把钱取出来了。”
took took it out oh yeah she she treated
她把投资当成
like a checking account Investments for
支票账户来用。对我来说，投资
are places to accumulate wealth I don't
是积累财富的地方，我不会从中
draw from it that's what a checking
取钱，取钱是支票
account is for so if what that is is
账户的用途。所以，
there's two parts to what your friend is
你朋友的话里有两个原因：
saying one is um mentally she's thinking
一是她可能在心理上认为
that this investment account is just
这个投资账户里的
money I can draw from if I need it so I
钱是需要的时候可以随时取用的，所以我建议你
would sort of gently change the way she
稍微改变一下她的
thinks about it the second is I
想法；二是我敢
guarantee her account structure is a
肯定，她的账户结构
little um subpar so here's how I would
有点…… 嗯，不太理想，所以我会这样
set it up this is in chapter 5 uh it's
设置，这在第五章里。呃，
all automation cuz trust me I don't want
全部都是自动化的，因为相信我，我不想
to spend time transferring money back
花时间来回转账，
and forth that's I don't spend any time
所以我不会在这方面浪费时间。
on that you get paid your money goes
你拿到工资后，钱会直接
into your checking account from your
存入你的支票账户，然后从
checking account it is automatically
支票账户自动
transferred to a savings account in fact
转到储蓄账户。实际上，
I have sub savings accounts for vacation
我还有专门的储蓄账户，用于度假、
car down payment all that stuff so you
汽车首付等等。这样你
have money set up for specific goals
就有专门的资金用于特定目标。
money is transferred to your investment
资金会转到你的投资
account it's transfer there I'm not
账户，我不会
going to touch that money I'm going to
动用这笔钱，我会让它
let it cook and then I have my
增值。然后我还有一些可以
guilt-free spending which is going out
自由支配的支出，比如
with friends whatever I love and my
和朋友出去玩，做任何我喜欢的事情。我的
credit card bill is automatically paid
信用卡账单每个月都会自动
off every single month that's how you
还款。这就是你
want to set it up it takes a couple of
想要的设置方式。
weeks to set everything up and then you
设置所有东西需要几周时间，之后你就再也
never have to think about it again C how
不用操心了。C，
can you prove to me that this is the way
你怎么向我证明这是
to make wealth what case studies have
致富之道？你有什么案例研究可以证明
long period of time is the path to
长期投资基金是通往
financial wealth because you know it's
财富的道路？因为你知道，就像
you said earlier about the paint drying
你之前说的油漆晾干的
thing The Narrative that we see about
例子一样。 我们经常听到这样的说法：
how why people and how people get rich
人们如何致富？
is you know they sell a company or they
他们卖掉公司，或者
have a lottery win or maybe they buy
中了彩票，或者买了
some cryptocurrency and it goes up yeah
加密货币，然后价格上涨。没错，
that's what we hear so that's what we're
我们听到的都是这样，所以我们
try and emulate totally we prove to me
试图完全模仿这种模式。我们要向我证明，
that that's that this fund strategy is
这种基金策略
better well there's there's a couple
更好。首先，有几点需要说明。
than a hundred about a hundred years
一百多年的研究
shows the returns of the stock market
表明，股市的回报率，
and the returns tend to be at least in
至少在
America they tend to be around
美国，通常在
11% 10 to 11% and if you take out
11%到11%之间。如果扣除
inflation you get about 7 to 8% per year
通货膨胀，年回报率大约在7%到8%之间。
now for anyone listening they go okay
现在，可能有人会问：
well what does that mean that number
好吧，那这个数字
means nothing to me 7% whatever if you
意味着什么？7%对我来说毫无意义。如果你
go right now and you Google investment
现在就去谷歌搜索“投资
calculator and you just plug in your age
计算器”，输入你的年龄，比如每月200到
you plug in let's say 200 300 bucks a
300美元，再
month and you plug in 7% return turn and
输入7%的回报率，然后
you just watch how that money grows you
观察这笔钱的增长，你
will be shocked Jack get me my phone I'm
会大吃一惊的。杰克，把手机给我，我
now okay so let's search for compound
现在就去试试。 我们来搜索一下
interest calculator and there's a really
复利计算器，找到一个非常
simple one this it's called money chimp
简单的，叫 Money Chimp。好的，好的，
okay okay I've got it all right all
我都找到了。好的，这里
right so there's four numbers we need to
有四个数字需要
fill out here let's take a look the
填写。我们来看一下。
first is current principle that means
第一个是本金，也就是
how much you've got in the bank I'm
你银行账户里的存款。我假设是
$5,000 and I'm going to start when I was
5000 美元，从我
16 because if IID saved my money when I
16 岁开始算起。因为如果我 16 岁的时候把钱存起来，
was 16 and not spent irr recklessly I
而不是乱花钱，我
think I could have had that $5,000 when
想我 16 岁的时候就能有 5000 美元了。
I 16 um annual Edition what does that
嗯，年化收益是什么
mean how much can you invest per year so
意思呢？你每年可以投资多少？
for most people they think about on a
大多数人都是
monthly basis they might say 200 bucks a
按月投资的，他们可能会说每月 200 美元，
month which would be $2,400 annual
那就是每年 2400 美元。
Edition okay so what do you want to say
好的，你想填多少？我填
I'm going to say can I say $5,000 yeah
5000 美元，嗯，也就是
that's you know about 400 bucks a month
每月 400 美元左右。
I think that that's reasonable I often
我觉得这个数额比较合理。我经常
find that with people making uh median
发现，对于那些收入处于中位数
or slightly above median salary that
或略高于中位数的人来说，这个数额比较合适。
there are hundreds of dollars of month
每月有几百美元的
of money that is unaccounted for that if
资金去向不明，如果
properly made intentional could be
妥善安排，就可以进行
invested so great 5,000 a year all right
投资，比如每年5000美元。
obviously I could have once I got past a
当然，等我过了
certain age I could have increased that
某个年龄，我就可以增加投资额了。
though so we're going to talk about that
所以我们接下来要讨论这个问题，
hold on to that idea okay how many years
记住这个概念。好，这是多少年？
this was you at 20 this was me at 16 oh
这是你20岁时的情况，这是我16岁时的情况。哦，
okay and how old are you today 30 okay
好的，你现在多大了？30岁。好的，
so 14 years let's just do it until today
所以是14年。我们就一直算到今天，
and we'll see what happens okay all
看看会发生什么。
right 14 years and then it says interest
好的，14年。然后上面写着
rate so what should we assume for that
利率，我们应该假设多少？
is that 8% yeah s to eight I I do seven
8%？嗯，还是8%？为了绝对保守，我假设7%，
just to be super conservative because I
因为我
never want to be surprised on the
不想在
downside right if anything I'm going to
亏损时措手不及。如果真有什么损失，我会
make more so 7% all right let's
赚得更多，所以7%。好的，我们来
calculate it okay what do you see damn
计算一下。你看到了什么？哇，
what do you see
你看到了什么？
$133,000 537 yeah that's what you would
133,537美元！是的，这就是你
have had right now now let's add some
现在应该拥有的金额。现在我们来补充一些
context so this is really important you
背景信息。这一点非常重要，你会
see a number that says
看到一个数字，上面写着：
$133,000 at age 30 yeah okay is that a
30岁就拥有13.3万美元，嗯，好吧，这
lot is that not hm I don't know let's
很多吗？嗯，我不知道。我们来
break it down at that point you started
分析一下。假设你一开始
with
有
$5,000 and you invested $5,000 per year
5000美元，每年投资5000美元，
we assumed no raises even though you
我们假设你没有加薪，尽管你
obviously made more than you made at age
显然比16岁时赚得多。嗯，
16 mhm weum assumed you stopped
我们假设你
investing at age 30 which is obviously
在30岁停止投资，这显然很
ridiculous and you end up with six
荒谬。最终你拥有了六位数的
figures let's play it out let's take it
财富。我们来算算，假设你投资到
40 so instead of 14 years you invested
40岁，而不是14年，那么你投资了
for 24 years what do you
24年。你
see I would have
看，我会有
$336,000 it's getting better from just
33.6万美元。这比
$5,000 a year it's not much it's
每年只投资5000美元要好得多，虽然不多，但已经很棒了。再说一遍，
fantastic again 400 bucks or so a month
每月400美元左右的投资
is very modest remember people's income
非常适中。记住，人们的收入
goes up typically in their 30s and 40s
通常会在30岁和40岁之间增长。
and if you already are investing a
如果你已经有
little bit automatically all you have to
自动投资的习惯，你只需要稍微
do is just tweak a number and it will
调整一下投资金额，每月只需额外花费
take an extra couple hundred three four
两三40美元，或者
500 bucks let's do one more let's go to
500美元。我们再来算一次。 我们先假设投资
34 years just because I want to see what
34年，因为我想看看会
happens and then we're going to play
发生什么，然后再
with the other numbers okay so investing
考虑其他数字。好的，假设
from the age of 16 until I'm 50 mhm I
从16岁投资到50岁，嗯，我
in my account yeah now I want to do the
的账户里会有73.6万美元。是的，现在我想
full the full thing I want to do a more
完整地模拟一下，我想用一个更
realistic number here so instead of 50
实际的数字。所以
we're going to go 49
我们不假设50岁，而是假设投资49
years that takes you to age 65 yeah okay
年，这样到65岁。好的，
and instead of $5,000 per year your
而且你的
income obviously went up from being 16
收入显然从16
years old so I'm going to pick a number
岁开始就增长了，不再是每年5000美元，所以我随便选一个数字，
out of thin air and and I'm going to
然后
tell you how I picked it I'm gonna say
告诉你我是怎么选的。我假设你
be $30,000 per year let me tell you why
每年投资3万美元，而不是5000美元。让我解释一下我为什么
I picked
选这个数字。
that in your early years you don't have
在你年轻的时候，你的
as much money but you were still
钱不多，但你一直在
investing a little bit which shows that
投资，这表明你很
you're dedicated as your income goes up
用心。随着收入的增长，
you're going to start proportionately
你会开始按比例
continuing to invest so at a certain
继续投资，所以到了某个
point your income will be really high
时候…… 你的收入会非常高，
and that will bring that average up
这会拉高平均值，所以
that's why I switched it to 30,000 per
我才把年投资额改成 3 万美元。
year I actually think this is quite
其实我觉得这个数额相当
modest but I'm going to go ahead and do
保守，但我还是会继续
it
这么做。假设
so here we have someone starting
有人从
investing at $5,000 they invest $30,000
5000 美元开始投资，每年投资 3 万美元，持续
year okay they grow it for 49 years at
49 年，年收益率为
7% do you know the
7%。你知道怎么
math no tell me
算吗？不知道，告诉我，是
12,330 so that's me starting with 5K
12330 美元。而我呢，从 5000 美元开始，
gradually ratcheting it up until I'm
逐步增加投资额，直到
investing well investing 30k on year a
每年平均投资 3 万美元，
year per average across those 49 years
持续 49 年。
yes which is a flaw in this because it's
没错，这其中有个缺陷，因为
so simple that money invested you're not
投资额太简单了，你一开始实际上不会投入那么多钱，
on you'll invest more later so you won't
后期会投入更多，所以最终的
amount less but we're talking 10 versus
金额可能只会略微减少一点。但我们说的是 1000 万美元和
12 million that's a lot of money and
1200 万美元之间的差别，这可是一大笔钱。
then if I got 8% instead of the 7% I'd
如果我的收益率是 8% 而不是 7%，我最终就能
have 17.4 million yeah but don't mess
得到 1740 万美元。没错，但别去管这个，因为……
with that cuz this is what this is what
这就是
people do they go well if I got 13% I'm
人们常做的事，他们会想，如果我能拿到13%的收益率，我
going to invest in
就去投资。千万别
I don't do that you're going to lose all
这么做，你会赔光所有
your money just stop 7% is safe it's
钱的，赶紧停下来。7%的收益率才是安全的，是
conservative that's why I am here that's
保守的。这就是我在这里的原因，也是
why I want to encourage people you don't
我想鼓励大家的原因。你不需要
need to juice your returns I hope you do
追求高收益。我希望你能
get 8% but I don't want you to count on
拿到8%的收益率，但我不想让你指望
that I want you to count on safe stable
这个。我希望你追求的是安全稳定的
returns and what matters for you is the
收益。对你来说重要的是
time you started early and the amount
你开始投资的时间，以及
you have a considerable amount to
你拥有的可观
invest you know the the biggest debt one
投资金额。你知道，最大的债务，
of the things I um I love saying this
我经常说的一点，就是
is ignorance and so I I heard this close
无知。
at this pitch years ago and this guy got
几年前，我在一个演讲中听到过类似的说法。一个人上台后，问女士：“您收入
ma'am he was like how much do you make
多少？”女士回答说：“
she was like $50,000 so he wrote $50,000
5万美元。”于是他
on the Whiteboard and then he wrote A
在白板上写下“5万美元”，然后在“5万美元”
Million Dollar on top of the 50,000 and
上面又写上“100万美元”，然后
he subtracted it and said $950,000 he
减去“100万美元”，最后说：“100万美元。” 他
said you pay life $950,000 every single
说，你每年要为生活付出95万美元，就因为你
year for not knowing how to make a
不知道如何年入一
million dollars a year and it was a
百万美元。这听起来很
crazy concept he was using it to close
疯狂，他用这个概念来结束
the audience but I like the most
演讲。但我认为，
expensive thing that all of us are
我们所有人付出的最昂贵的代价，
paying for is the information that we
是我们
don't know and that's like both
不知道的信息。这既令人
frightening and also incredibly exciting
恐惧，又令人无比兴奋，就像
like fish in the best ponds right like a
最好的池塘里的鱼一样，一个
good fisherman knows where to fish and a
好的渔夫知道在哪里捕鱼。
different way of saying it is find the
换句话说，就是找到
most and I'm sure you've heard this have
最珍惜你所拥有的人。我相信你们都听过这个故事，
you heard the story of the the father
你们听过父子
and the son with the car no okay so
俩关于车的故事吗？没有？好吧，也许
maybe I have I enough detail it's good
我讲得够详细了。故事是这样的：一位
it's good so there's there's a father
父亲
who gifts his son an old beat up car and
送给儿子一辆破旧的汽车，
he says you know hey I don't know if it
他说：“嘿，我不知道它还能
drives or not but you can take it down
不能开，但你可以把它开
to the um the dealership down the street
到街角的汽车经销店，
see if you can trade and get some money
看看能不能换点钱。”儿子说：“
he was like okay so he goes down the
好的。”于是他去了
street goes to the dealership they say
街角的汽车经销店，他们说：“
we'll give you a th000 bucks for it and
我们会给你……” 一千块钱，
he come you know hears him out comes
他听完他的话
back home he's like Dad they said give
回家后说：“爸，他们说给
me a th bucks he's like okay he's like
我一千块钱。”他说：“好吧。”他说：“
go to the impound yard where they you
去汽车拆解场，就是那种
know break the cars up just for Metal
专门拆车卖金属的地方。”
He's like see what they'll give you goes
他说：“看看他们给你多少钱。”他去了
there and uh the guy's like ah I don't
那里，那人说：“呃，我不
know this might be500 Buck of metal kid
知道，这玩意儿可能值五百块钱。”孩子
like you know comes back home he's like
回家后说：“
Dad you know he said it was going to be
爸，你知道，他说
$500 he's like okay he's like hey go
五百块钱。”他说：“好吧。”他说：“嘿，
down the street to that uh that antique
去街对面那家古董
uh dealership see if they've got
车行看看，看他们有没有二手车。”他说：“
anything that use carlot he's like okay
好的。”
so he goes down there talks to the guy
于是他去了那里，和那人聊了聊，
comes back home super excited he's like
回家后兴奋极了，他说：“
Dad you won't believe it he's like this
爸，你肯定不信！”他说：“这
is a historic car there's only like 10
是一辆古董车，现在只剩下十辆了！”
of them left he's like it's worth
他说：“这辆车值
$100,000 and so the father smiles and
十万美元！”父亲笑了，然后说……
he's like and the lesson I want you to
我想让你
know is that it's not necessarily who
明白的一点是，这并不一定取决于
you are but the people that value you
你是谁，而是…… 那些最重视你的人，
the most and so you can talk to
所以你可以和
different people and go to the people
不同的人交谈，去找那些
who value you and I just I I love that
重视你的人。我喜欢这个
story because from a it's a Hu it's a
故事，因为它从
huge business story in terms of like
商业角度来说，就像是去鱼多的地方
sell sell the where the fish are where
卖东西，去
the big fish are like if you if you're
大鱼多的地方卖东西。如果你想
going to go Hook Fish go to go where the
钓到鱼，就去钓到
whales are um it takes the same work but
鲸鱼。这需要付出同样的努力，但
a lot of it's just belief people don't
很多时候只是信念的问题。人们不
think it's possible and so a lot of
相信这是可能的，所以很多
times you have to just keep leveling up
时候你必须不断提升自己。当你卖出第一件价值
and you sell your first $110,000 thing
11 万美元的东西，卖出第一件价值
you sell your first $100,000 thing sell
10 万美元的东西，卖出
your first multi-million dollar package
第一件价值数百万美元的东西，
you realize it's the exact same thing
你会发现它们本质上是一样的。所以，
it's just so maybe if I'm list if
如果我列出清单，或者
anybody's listing right now it is the
现在有人列出清单，那也是一样的，完全一样。
sometimes it's
有时候会更
easier it's normally easier like you
容易，通常情况下会更容易。你
know you've seen that Meme that says
知道，你肯定看过那个梗图，上面写着：
like uh so what exactly am I going to be
呃，我花
getting for this $50 thing right and
50 美元到底能买到什么？
then it's like uh $50,000 clients like
然后…… 呃，像昨天那种价值五万美元的客户，就像“
wire scent yesterday like what do you
你
else do you need like it's and that's
还需要什么？”一样，这
totally true um but I think there's a
完全属实。嗯，但我认为
skill in understanding where to
懂得去哪里“
fish so a skill um information it's
钓鱼”也是一种技巧，所以这是一种技巧，嗯，信息，就是
information it's even knowing that there
信息，甚至知道那边还有
was another Lake over there in part and
另一个湖。这就是为什么
and that's why like listening to
倾听
conversations like this is so valuable
这样的对话
for people because it lifts a curtain
对人们如此有价值，因为它揭开了一层面纱，
and you go what the [__] you guys were
你会想：你们这些家伙一直在
behind here the whole time partying
后面开派对，
that's what my business life has been
这到底是怎么回事？我的事业生涯就是这样，
like it's like gradually like I think I
就像我曾经在
heard Kevin Hart describe on Joe Rogan
乔·罗根的节目里听到凯文·哈特描述的那样，
one time where he said there's this
他说，还有
other room yeah where these people
另一个房间，是的，里面的人在
playing this other set of money games
玩另一套金钱游戏。
yeah and then when you get in that room
当你进入那个房间时，
you get you're almost pissed off that
你会几乎生气，因为
nobody told you this room existed did
没人告诉你这个房间的存在。
but then there's another door
但然后还有另一扇门。
yeah and then you get through there
然后你穿过那扇门，
maybe a couple of years later and you
可能几年后，你会
find these other people these [__]
发现这些人，这些
billionaires that playing another set of
亿万富翁，在玩另一套
games and you're going what and they're
游戏。你会想：什么？他们正在
chilling yeah they're just smoking
放松，是的，他们只是在抽烟。
cigars they're not even doing any hard
雪茄，他们甚至都没干什么
work and you go tell me the games that
苦差事，你去告诉我
you guys have been playing in here yeah
你们在这里玩的是什么游戏？是啊，
and then again the frustration is and
然后，挫败感又来了，
that's kind of what I feel like in my
这有点像我在
business life it's been like where at
商业生活中的感受。一
the jump I'm charging I don't know I
开始，我收费，我不知道，我
remember my first we found our first
记得我的第一个客户，我们找到了
deck from 2014 charging I remember the
2014年的第一个牌组，我记得
package we did gold silver and bronze it
我们当时的套餐，金、银、铜，
was like you know like $200 package for
你知道，比如200美元的套餐，提供一些
like support and then $500 and then the
支持，然后是500美元的，还有
gold package where we threw everything
金套餐，我们把所有东西都打包了，
in for $1,000 and I remember my one of
1000美元。我记得我
my first clients um accepting that and
的第一个客户接受了这个套餐。
then I think today like the only
然后我觉得今天唯一的
difference okay there's skills that have
区别是，好吧，技能
increased but information is the big
提高了，但信息才是最重要的，
thing knowing how to do it you know
知道如何去做。你知道，
um when you think about curtains that
当你想到那些
have lifted that have really shifted the
真正改变了
games you play from a value money
你从性价比角度所玩游戏的幕布时，嗯，就像
perspective mhm like where someone's Ed
有人说“Ed
the Lights On You [__] of course yeah is
the Lights On You Fuck”一样。当然，还有什么
there anything else that comes to
其他想法吗？
mind I will answer it with the stair
我会用阶梯式的方法来回答，
steps of how each order of magnitude
每个数量级的
change in my income so when I went from
变化是如何发生的。 收入方面，当我从
being an employee to self-employed I
雇员转为自雇人士时，我的
went from making four figures a month to
月收入从四位数增长到
five figures a month and that was for me
五位数。对我来说，这就像
just like I'm now in control the level
我现在掌控一切一样。
above that was I started having other
更高一级的是，我开始雇佣其他
people who worked for me and then went
人为我工作，然后
to six figures a month right and then
月收入达到了六位数，对吧？之后我一直保持在这个水平，做着
turnaround business still had the same
扭亏为盈的业务，仍然保持着相同的
organizational structure had another
组织结构，但
degree of Leverage and so the next
杠杆作用又提升了一层。下一个
degree of Leverage was that I started
杠杆作用是我开始
licensing so it was digital right so the
授权，也就是数字化产品，对吧？所以
cost for you cost of goods is basically
你的成本（商品成本）基本上
nothing but all of these things are
为零。但所有这些都与
about leverage and so this is like one
杠杆有关，这可以说是
of my favorite topics in the whole world
我最喜欢的话题之一。
but if we Define leverage as the
如果我们把杠杆定义为
difference between what you put in and
投入和
what you get out so if you have a lot of
产出之间的差值，那么如果你拥有高杠杆，
Leverage you put a little bit in you get
你投入少就能获得
a lot out if you have no leverage or low
多；如果你没有杠杆或
leverage you put a lot in you get a
杠杆低，你投入多却
little bit out and a lot of times people
产出少。很多时候，
who are listening to this and are not
正在听我讲话的人，如果收入
making as much money as they want
不如预期，
they're putting lots of input in and not
他们投入了很多，但
getting a lot out they have low Leverage
产出却很少，他们错失了杠杆
opportunities and so understanding how
机会。所以，了解如何
to get more for what you put in is the
获得高杠杆至关重要。 投入越多，回报越大，这就是整个
game overall and so the first level that
游戏的精髓所在。
I described was Labor it's just work
我之前提到的第一层是劳动力，也就是工作。一开始
first I was working for someone else
我为别人工作，
then I worked for myself then I got
后来自己创业，再后来我雇佣
other people to work for me first level
其他人为我工作。
each of those levels was more leverage
每一层都意味着更高的杠杆。
above that I had media which is the
再往上一层，我拥有媒体，也就是
thing that I was licensing out so
我授权出去的东西。这又增加了一层
another degree of Leverage I made it
杠杆：我
once and I could license it out Infinity
一次创作，就可以无限授权。
on top of that I have capital I can take
除此之外，我还有资本，我可以随时获取
capital I don't have to sacrifice time
资本，无需牺牲时间就能有所收获，
in order to get something for it so it's
所以这是
high input output um above that would be
高投入高回报的模式。再往上一层，就是
some sort of Technology you build the
某种技术。
code once in theory obviously you
理论上，你只需编写一次代码，当然，你可以
continue to improve the code but
不断改进代码，但
theoretically you build the thing once
理论上，你只需开发一次，就可以让
and then a million people can use it and
一百万人使用。
so you want to Stack as many types of
所以，你要尽可能多地叠加各种
Leverage as you can and as much of them
杠杆，
as you can because like Joe Rogan also
因为像乔·罗根这样的人也
has a show and somebody else has a
有自己的节目，还有人有自己的
podcast they both technically are using
播客，他们实际上都在利用
media as their as their as their vehicle
媒体作为
for leverage but he has significantly
杠杆工具，但乔·罗根的媒体资源要丰富得多。
more of it so it's not just like I'm
所以，这并不是说我要把
going to use all these right yeah but
所有这些都用上，对吧？
it's also how much and to what degree
多少，程度如何？
but like Facebook had other people's
但就像Facebook利用了别人的
money he used media had other people's
钱，利用了媒体，利用了别人的
work Max leverage Amazon same thing
劳动成果。亚马逊也是如此，
right they used every element of
他们利用了杠杆的每一种元素，
Leverage and they maxed all of them out
并且都发挥到了极致。
and um that's that's at least the the
嗯，这至少是
curtain that and nval talks about this
表面现象。
if you're familiar with Nal rant um he
如果你熟悉Nal Rant，他谈到过这些，他把这些称为
the P the elements of Leverage or four
杠杆的要素，或者说四种
types of Leverage um and understanding
杠杆类型。
that for me has kind of been a blueprint
对我来说，理解这一点就像是
for wealth overall and then you know
财富蓝图。然后，你知道，
Capital there's degrees of capital right
资本也有不同的层次。
like you first you can get friends and
首先，你可以从亲朋好友那里
family to give you money then you can
获得资金；然后，你
get you know institutional money and
可以获得机构资金；
then you can get public money right
最后，你可以获得公众资金，比如
which you know you saw like the IPO
IPO
money like the fact that the NASDAQ was
资金，就像纳斯达克和
Forex uh the dorf exchange is that where
外汇市场（也就是道格拉斯交易所）那样。
significantly more capital in that
这些
market and so it same work more zeros um
市场拥有更多的资本，所以它能带来更多的收益。
and so I love this topic because I think
我喜欢这个话题，因为我认为，从
that that's fundamentally like the
根本上来说，那些
people who move faster in life don't
在生活中行动更快的人，
actually move faster than get more for
实际上并没有…… 行动要比每一步都追求更多更快。
step if right now you want to find where
如果你现在想找到那个
is your unfair bet that can make you
能让你凭借自身技能赚取百万财富的“不公平赌注”，而
your Millions with your skill
你的技能是
set that nobody else in the world can
世界上
replicate except you here's what I need
除了你之外无人能及的，那么
I would need a whiteboard I would need a
我需要：一块白板，一支
pen which I would do if I was you and I
笔（如果我是你，我会这么做），还有
would need a smart friend perfect like
一个聪明的朋友，完美！就像
so I've got Stephen here and at the top
这样，我把斯蒂芬放在这里。在
of the right whiteboard I would write on
白板右侧的顶部，我会写下“
this side skills oh my God you're going
技能”（哦，我的天，你会
to see my handwriting like a doctor and
看到我那像医生一样的字迹），然后
on this side I would write money M and I
在另一侧写下“金钱”（M），我
would start writing down all the things
会开始写下我们所有
that we're brilliant at so let's pretend
擅长的事情。假设
it's it's stepen here and we'll pretend
这是斯蒂芬，我们假设
like you don't have all the things that
你没有你现在拥有的所有技能，
you have but your core skill set you
但你的核心技能是……你
could put your hand on the screen by the
可以把手放在屏幕上。对了，这
way oh it makes me nervous am I am I
让我有点紧张。我这样
doing this like a boomer I am the
做像个老古董吗？我的
handwriting is a little bit it's giving
字迹有点像
doctor so I'm yeah look at that okay so
医生，所以……是的，看看吧，好吧，真
embarrassing okay so social media right
尴尬。社交媒体，对吧？
you're incredible at social media what
你在社交媒体方面非常出色，还有什么呢？
else are you probably good at well you
你可能很擅长……嗯，你
know a lot of people you've got a
认识很多人，你有人
network what else well it's not just
脉。还有什么呢？嗯，
just social media though it's actually a
不仅仅是社交媒体，实际上还有
few particular things it's like YouTube
一些特定的东西，比如YouTube。
and I think you're one of the best in
我认为你是
the world at short form video right
短视频领域的世界顶尖高手之一，对吧？
you're also one of the best in the world
你也是
datadriven social media strategy so you
数据驱动型社交媒体策略领域的世界顶尖高手之一，所以你
can kind of say upfront hey we think
可以直接说：“嘿，我们认为
this is going to go viral because the
这个视频会爆红，因为
data says this thing over here what else
数据显示这个。”
is Stephen good at he's charismatic he
斯蒂芬还有什么其他特长？他很有魅力，
can probably get people to agree to
可能只要跟人聊聊就能让他们同意一些
things just by talking to them you know
事情。你知道吗？还有什么？
what what else uh British ACC you know
嗯，英国ACC（英国广告公司）。
so probably you want more in-person
所以你可能更想要面对面的
interaction because uh we've got you
互动，因为我们有
know uh a very charismatic person what
一个非常有魅力的人。
else is Stephen really good at well he
斯蒂芬还有什么特别擅长的？嗯，他会
asks a lot of questions this is my hinge
问很多问题。顺便说一下，这是我的Hinge个人
profile by the way I'm totally just
资料，我完全是
gonna copy and paste St yeah good-look
复制粘贴的。是的，看起来不错，真
funny you know yeah exactly so so we'll
有趣。你知道，是的，没错。所以我们就说
just say these there's a lot more deal
这些吧，还有很多合作
flow but let's just pretend that all
机会，但我们假设
you're good at is social media you're
你只擅长这些。 你擅长利用社交媒体
good at getting to people which is a
接触人脉，这是一个人脉
network you don't even have to know rich
网络，你甚至不需要认识
people just can you get to them you're
有钱人，只要你能接触到他们就行。你很有
charismatic you're data driven okay
魅力，你又以数据为导向。
great we've got all these skills now how
好的，我们掌握了所有这些技能，现在
could we apply these skills to get the
我们该如何运用这些技能来赚取尽可能
most money humanly possible and I would
多的钱呢？我会
do exactly what you said so how do you
完全按照你说的去做。那么，如何才能
figure out most money humanly possible
赚到尽可能多的钱呢？这包含
it's two things it's the how would I do
两方面：一是“我该怎么做”，二
this it's the size of the
是“问题的大小”，三
problem it is the value of the
是“解决方案的价值”。很
solution interesting okay and so if I'm
有意思。好的，假设我把
I give your social media media skills to
你的社交媒体技能运用到
a trade or service business M I'm not
一家贸易或服务企业，我肯定
going to make that much money how do I
赚不到多少钱。我怎么
know I'm not going to make that much
知道我赚不到那么多
money because I'm going to go look up
钱呢？因为我会
online what is the average revenue of
上网查一下这家企业的平均收入
this business and the average profit
和平均
margin yeah now you probably didn't even
利润率。是的，你可能在
think this way when you were thinking
思考这个问题的时候根本没想过这一点，
about it but you guys look online right
但你们现在就上网查一下，
a biotech company in average revenue let
一家生物科技公司的平均利润率是多少？平均收入是多少？让
me tell you what it is it's going to be
我来告诉你答案。大概是这样的。
like 50 to 80%
50%到80%，
millions that you could potentially get
你有可能获得数亿美元的潜在收益，
Trade Services business a lot less yeah
贸易服务业务的收益要少得多。
and so that's where I would start skills
所以，这就是我的切入点。技能
plus money really equals to three things
加上资金实际上等于三个因素：
business and profitability of the
企业的行业规模和盈利能力。
business and I would play this game and
我会玩这个游戏，具体做法
what that might look like is you go okay
是：
I know that I have some friends in
我知道我有一些朋友，我们去
the most cash in Silicon Valley in on
硅谷和华尔街那些资金最雄厚的地方看看，
Wall Street if they could make a lot
如果他们能获得更多关注，就能赚到更多
more money if they had a lot more
钱。
attention because what I'm selling is
因为我卖的是
attention I want to get to the people
关注度，我想找到那些
who can make the most money with the
能用最多关注度赚最多钱的人。
most attention and that means that I'm
这意味着我
not going to go to Walmart only has 6%
不会去利润率只有6%的
margins I'm going to go to the highest
沃尔玛，我会去找
person that I could get to and it'd be
我能接触到的最高层级的人。
fun if anybody's listening to this right
如果有人正在听这段话，不妨
now try it like tag Stephen and I in
试试，在Instagram故事里标记我和Stephen，分享
your stories on Instagram of your little
你们的小
charts and let's see and I'll give
图表，看看结果如何。我会给
feedback anybody that tags me in it if
所有标记我的人反馈，比如“
you're like here's the here's what I
这是……这是……” 我
think my skill is here's what I think
认为我的技能是这样的，我对
the industry is I'll tell you one way or
这个行业的看法是这样的，我会告诉你，
another and it can be fun you can see
这很有趣，你可以
other people's examples live so people
实时看到其他人的例子，这样那些
people that are only listening on audio
只听音频
and and that can't see what the um this
而看不到的人也能明白。嗯，就像
you've just drawn on this iPad um on one
你刚才在这个iPad上潦草画的字一样，
hand you have you list your skills and
一边列出你的技能，
then on the second side you're listing
另一边列出
the ways you believe you could make the
你认为可以利用
most money from those skills based on
这些技能赚最多钱的方法，这取决于
the size of the problem you'd be solving
你要用这些技能解决的问题的大小
with them and the value of the solution
和解决方案的价值。举个
so for example let me let me try and
例子，我来
play this game with you then so okay so
和你玩这个游戏。好的，我
I am a writer so I'm going to do my
是一名作家，所以我会在左边写我的
skills on the left hand I'm a writer and
技能，我是一名作家，
on right I'm going to write money yep
右边我会写赚钱的方法。是的，
I'm a writer I'm really good at writing
我是一名作家，我非常擅长写作，嗯，就是这样。
stuff um that's it and I kind of get I
我对
kind of get the internet so I kind of
互联网也略知一二，所以我
understand LinkedIn blogs and stuff like
了解LinkedIn、博客之类的东西，
that but that's it I'm a writer let's go
但仅此而已。我是一名作家，我们来谈谈最糟糕的情况是什么。
be the worst thing you could do if
如果
you're a writer to make no money to make
你是个作家，你可以做一件赚
no money cuz sometimes it's easier to do
不到钱的事，因为有时候做
the negative okay working for a local
负面的事更容易些。好吧，给地方
news yeah local I was thinking like
新闻工作，对，是地方新闻。我想的是，像
fiction you know really hard to make
奇幻小说，你可以写那种虚构作品，你知道，那种很难
money in you could write for a local
赚钱的小说，你可以给地方
newspaper that's an even worse idea so I
报纸写稿，那更糟糕。所以我
like that so now you've got your your
喜欢这个主意。现在你有了
bottom tier right which is like 14 bucks
最低档的，对吧，大概每小时14美元左右。
an hour or something like that now if
现在如果
you look about I mean you could Google
你四处看看，我的意思是，你可以谷歌一下“
writers I bet the thing you'd find on
作家收入最高的工作是什么”，我敢打赌你会找到
top copywriter why I got a better one oh
顶级文案撰稿人。为什么我找到了更好的？哦，
what's the better one do you know why I
更好的是什么？你知道我为什么
know this because when I was in working
知道吗？因为我以前在一家
in biotch we couldn't hire one which is
公司工作的时候，我们招不到
a medical writer oh oh so smart hypers
医学撰稿人。哦，哦，多么聪明、高度专业化啊！说实话，我们招不到一个
specialized honestly we so a typical
普通的文案
copywriter when I was working in my
撰稿人。我在我的
social media company we might pay entry
社交媒体公司工作的时候，我们可能给入门
level £25,000 which is probably about
级的薪水是25000英镑，大概是
$35,000 okay a medical writer someone
35000美元。好吧，医学撰稿人，一个
that can write about the psilocybin
能写关于裸盖菇素
compound in my psychedelics business
化合物的人。 迷幻药行业
would get paid
能赚到
$150,000 or more we just couldn't find
15 万美元甚至更多，我们只是找不到合适的人。
some we found loads of people that could
我们找到了很多会
write yeah but nobody that had within
写作的人，但就是找不到具备相关
their skill stack even though it's quite
技能的人。虽然
easy to teach the ability to write using
用医学术语写作很容易，但这
doesn't mean you need a medical degree
并不意味着你需要医学学位。
become a medical writer in a month if
如果你真的下定决心，一个月就能学会如何写作，成为一名医学撰稿人。
you really committed yourself to it so
所以这
that's the top true and same with
是最靠谱的。
Finance we go to the things we know so
金融行业也是如此，我们总是选择自己熟悉的领域。比如
you know biotechs you know there's a
生物科技，我知道那里有个
niche there I know finance and I know
细分市场；我了解金融，也知道
that again it's one of the highest
它是
paying Industries so a financial writer
收入最高的行业之一。那么，金融撰稿人会是什么样的呢？
probably an investor update yes right
大概就是会写投资者报告的人吧。没错，
yeah yeah yeah so hugely lucrative and
收入非常可观。还有一点，
guess I didn't even think about this
我
before it would be like size of the
之前可能没想过，那就是问题的大小、
solution and then it would also be
解决方案的价值，以及
structure of your job so like if you're
工作的结构。比如，如果你是一名
a copywriter I wouldn't take a job for
文案撰稿人，我不会接受
35k what would I do I would say hey pay
3.5 万美元的年薪，那我该怎么办？ 我会说，嘿，给
me what is the salary you want to offer
我钱，你想给我多少薪水？
35,000 I'll take 10,000 so I can eat
35000？我拿10000，这样我才能吃饭，
because I'm hungry but can I have a
因为我饿了。但是，我能不能从
percentage of The Upside that I drive
我
above and beyond goal so if I'm going to
超出目标的部分中抽取一定比例的收益？比如，如果我
write copy that converts into Revenue
写一些能转化为收入的文案，
like I'm going to write a funnel for
比如我为
your biotech company or I'm going to
你的生物科技公司写一个销售漏斗，或者我为
write a funnel to get investors for you
你写一个吸引投资者的销售漏斗，
if right now per month you get $100,000
如果现在你每个月通过这个漏斗赚10万美元，那你是不是可以额外给
pay me an extra 10% of everything I
我超出
drive above your 100K so I think that's
10万美元部分的10%作为佣金？我认为这是
another way you can make more money is
另一种赚钱的方法，那就是更
getting smarter on deal
聪明地进行交易
structuring well that's actually when I
结构设计。实际上，我刚
moved into biotch how I got paid and
进入生物科技行业的时候就是这么拿钱的。
when I talked about a thou being paid a
我之前说过，我的收入比以前高出一
thousand times more than I would have
千倍，那是
previously it's because was the way I
因为我的
got paid was in options in the IPO
报酬是以IPO期权的形式获得的。
brilliant yeah so I got given in that
太棒了！是的，我在那家
particular company I got given 400,000
公司获得了40万股
shares effectively in the company at a
股票，相当于以某个价格买入了该公司的股份。
certain price um and so when the company
嗯，所以当公司在
July 20 I don't know 21 or something
2020年7月（也可能是2021年）在纳斯达克上市，估值32亿美元的时候，
even though I'd only worked in the
尽管我只在那家
company for about six months just
公司工作了大约六个月，只是
helping them build out the marketing
帮他们组建市场营销
team I think my like net return was on
团队，但我认为我当时的净收益（按
the equity value at the time was quite
股权价值计算）
close to 10 million so 6 months work 10
接近1000万美元，也就是6个月的工作，1000万美元的
million return because I you know and
回报。你知道，
the re really really the reason I did it
我做这件事的真正原因是我
was CU so interested in psychedelics but
对迷幻药很感兴趣，但这让
it just opened my eyes to the fact that
我意识到，
any kid with social media skills and
任何一个懂社交媒体、
that knew how to structure a deal with
懂得如何与
these people could have walked in there
这些人达成交易的年轻人，都可以走进去
and said give me some stock in this IPO
说：“给我一些IPO的股票，
and I'll run your social media for six
我来帮你们运营6个月的社交媒体。”
months you're so right could have change
你说得太对了，这完全可以改变
your life yeah and it's it's something
你的人生。是的，
I'm struggling with trying to get people
我现在一直在努力让人们
to understand right now is that even if
理解这一点：即使
you never buy a business which is what
你从未收购过一家公司（
people fixate on well I haven't bought a
人们总是纠结于此，但我还没收购过
business yet I haven't bought a business
公司，我还没收购过公司），
yet it's like God you're never going to
你也永远不会
regret learning how to do
后悔。 学习如何做
deals you're never going to it's I think
你永远不会参与的交易，我认为
that is the most valuable skill set in
这是世界上最有价值的技能，
the world I completely agree and it's so
我完全同意。
unfair that people don't know about it
人们不知道这一点
it's so unfair but it's also your fault
太不公平了，真的太不公平了。但如果
if you don't know about it because
你不知道，那也是你的错，因为
anymore it used to be gatekeep like when
现在没有人把这些信息藏起来了。以前确实存在这种把关，比如
I first started off in private Equity I
我刚开始做私募股权的时候，我根本
wasn't allowed in the rooms where they
不被允许进入他们
were actually doing the deals and the
实际进行交易和讨论
terms and if I wanted to see what the
条款的房间。如果我想了解
final terms were like I had to kind of
最终条款，就得想办法，
you know sweet talk my way into figuring
你知道的，用甜言蜜语套取
out how they structured it but it's an
他们是如何构建交易结构的。但那完全是
unknown unkknown
未知数，
so before I knew I didn't know that I
所以在我知道之前，我根本不知道自己不知道。是的，没错，确实如此。
very true but now I think there's enough
但现在，我认为有足够多的
people out there talking about it where
人在谈论这个话题，
you're like I mean if you think about
你会想，
whether you like Donald Trump or not
不管你喜不喜欢唐纳德·特朗普，
what is he really good at deals the art
他真正擅长的是什么？
of the deal like it it that's it and
交易的艺术，就是这样。还有
that is what Mo I mean Elon Musk how
埃隆·马斯克，
does Tesla actually make money they make
特斯拉究竟是如何赚钱的？ 他
money through credits through credits
通过太阳能税收抵免赚钱，
for solar so he was able to survive for
所以他才能在
those 10 years of building that company
创建公司的十年间维持运营，
because he has some of the best solar
因为他与政府谈判获得了世界上最好的太阳能
tax credits in the world that he
税收抵免政策。
negotiated with the government so where
那么，
does one go then where does a
一个正在
25-year-old kid listening to this go to
听我讲解的25岁年轻人该如何
learn how to make deals well I have a
学习如何做交易呢？嗯，我有一
book coming out yeah called Main Street
本书即将出版，叫做《大街上的
millionaire yes exciting I know and we
百万富翁》，是的，听起来很激动人心，我知道。我们还有一些其他的
have we have stuff we can tell them
东西，
about that later too okay well I'm going
以后可以再跟大家分享。好的，我会在
to link Main Street millionaire below so
下面附上《大街上的百万富翁》的链接，方便
everyone can pre-order it I've
大家预购。我已经
pre-ordered I think 10 or 20 copies of
预购了大概10到20本，
it maybe a couple more um but that's
可能还会再多几本。这本书大概
like 30 bucks and you learn almost
30美元，你可以从中学习到几乎
everything you need to know about doing
所有关于如何做
a deal to start and that book is only
交易的知识。这本书只包含了
what you need to know I made it on
你真正需要知道的内容，我
purpose not really long not overly
特意把它写得不长也不
intense it is exactly what you need to
复杂，它正是你需要
know and then if you like learning deal
知道的。如果你喜欢学习交易技巧，
making and you like that book then you
也喜欢这本书，那么你可以
go to contrarian thinking.com and we
访问contrarianthinking.com，我们
have courses and free newsletters and a
有课程、免费简讯和一个
community all about buying businesses um
关于收购企业的社区。
but that's where you should
这就是你应该
start the other thing I I came to learn
开始的地方。我后来学到的另一件事
is I got money and I it was almost like
是，当我有了钱，就好像
someone pulled the curtain back for me
有人为我揭开了帷幕，让我看到了
is how wealthy
富人是如何
individuals play the TX game oh my gosh
玩转税务游戏的。天哪，这简直就是一场
and it's a tax game that the average
普通人完全不了解的税务游戏。
to talk about money tax avoidance is a
说到钱，避税是
key skill to Building Wealth and by the
积累财富的关键技能。
way we don't talk about I I speak openly
顺便说一句，我们不谈论避税，我公开
about my I won't call it tax avoidance
谈论我的税务策略，我不会称之为避税，
but my Tax Strategies if you're you know
而是我的税务策略。你知道，
it's like they said if you're a prison
就像他们说的，如果你身处
of War you have an obligation to escape
战俘营，你有义务逃跑；
if you're trying to build wealth you
如果你想积累财富，你
have an obligation to pay as little tax
有义务尽可能少缴税，当然要
as possible do it legally but Apple will
合法地做到。但苹果公司会将
issue their IP to Apple International in
他们的知识产权授权给位于爱尔兰的苹果国际公司，
Ireland and then they will use apple
然后苹果国际公司再将
Ireland they will license their IP to
他们的知识产权授权给
America charge them tens of billions of
美国，向美国收取数百亿
dollars thereby increasing the income of
美元的费用，从而以
Apple Ireland at a lower tax rate and
较低的税率增加苹果爱尔兰公司的收入，同时
decreasing the income in the US thereby
降低美国的收入，从而
lowering their overall tax rate that is
降低他们的整体税率。这
pure tax
纯粹是避税。
avoidance every organization every
每个组织、每个
corporation does this to the hilt and so
公司都在竭尽全力地这样做，
should you by the way I will vote for
你也应该这样做。顺便说一句，我会 投票给
people who have an alternative minimum
那些支持替代性最低
tax we have to raise taxes on
税的人，我们必须提高
corporations the 25 wealthiest Americans
企业税。美国最富有的25人
pay between 6 and 8% tax rate what are
缴纳6%到8%的税率，
the tax games they're playing oh just
他们到底在玩什么避税游戏？哦，只有
the rich people there's a bunch of them
富人，他们人数众多。
first and foremost it's you buy stocks
首先，他们买股票，却
you never sell them you borrow against
从不卖，而是用股票作抵押借款。
them okay explain that to me like I'm a
好，给我解释一下，就像给我一个
10-year-old so sure you own $100 an
10岁的孩子解释一样。假设你持有价值100美元的
Amazon stock yeah you need money to buy
亚马逊股票，你需要钱去买
something instead of selling the stock
东西，而不是卖掉股票。如果股票
and it say it's gone up 50% I say it's
上涨了50%，我认为它
doubled you would have to realize a
翻了一番，你就必须实现
capital gain and pay long-term capital
资本利得，并
gains on that $50 gain no just borrow
为这50美元的收益缴纳长期资本利得税。不，你可以用
against it and let the stock continue to
它作抵押借款，让股票继续
grow and you pay a little bit of
增长，你只需支付少量
Interest hopefully from your current
利息，最好是从你目前的
income but basically it's invest borrow
收入中支付。但基本上…… 投资、
against it and die put it into a a trust
抵押贷款、把钱放进信托，
and then pass it on to your kids there's
然后传给你的孩子。有
a lot of um State Arbitrage Jeff Bezos
很多州套利。杰夫·贝佐斯
just moved to Florida to spend more time
刚搬到佛罗里达，为了多陪陪他
with Dad isn't that sweet Stephen isn't
爸，这难道不暖心吗？斯蒂芬·贝佐斯也没那么好，
that nice no it has nothing to do with
不，这跟
his father give me a [__] break he
他爸没关系，别开玩笑了。他
aggregated $160 billion in wealth he
积累了1600亿美元的财富，在华盛顿州他
would pay about another eight or 10% in
还要再交8%到10%的
state taxes in Washington because he's
州税，因为他
got to leverage the public school system
要利用公立学校系统、
the University of Washington the Seattle
华盛顿大学、西雅图-
Tacoma Airport the hospital system but
塔科马机场和医院系统。但
in the US you're allowed to piece out to
在美国，你可以搬到
Texas or Florida and pay no income tax
德克萨斯州或佛罗里达州，不用交所得税。
so all the people [__] Post in
所以所有在
California or New York show me someone
加州或纽约混日子的人，给我找个
who's CR all of a sudden can't handle
突然受不了
San Francisco politics I'm going to show
旧金山政治的人。我给
you someone who needs to recognize a
你找个需要确认
capital gain and has all of a sudden
资本收益，却突然
decided they like like Texas politics
喜欢上德克萨斯州政治的人。
it's really not very it's very
这真的太
disingenuous there's uh the tax loophole
虚伪了。美国有个税收漏洞，
I've leveraged in the US there's
我利用了它，有个叫
something called 122 or qualified small
122条款的东西。 合格小型
business so when I started L2 what's L2
企业。所以，当我创办L2时，L2是什么？
L2 is my analytics company I started it
L2是我的分析公司。我创办它时
I invested a small amount of money um uh
投入了一小笔钱，嗯，
because it was a business worth F less
因为这家公司的价值不到
than 50 million your business would
5000万美元。如果你持有该公司股票超过5年，你的公司
qualify in the US as qsb small business
在美国就符合QSB（合格小型企业）的资格。
company for longer than 5 years when you
当你
sell it the first 10 million or 10 times
出售股票时，前1000万美元或
the basis are taxfree so the first 10
成本的10倍是免税的。所以
million out of L2 was tax-free
L2的前1000万美元是免税的。这
zero that makes no sense if that sounds
听起来很奇怪，
like we're screwing the middle class
好像我们在坑害中产阶级，
trust your instincts I invested in a
相信你的直觉。我投资了一家
company brought a company out of
公司，让它
are to turn rich people into super rich
摆脱了破产困境。我投资了250万美元，前2500万美元非常幸运，公司以高价售出，前2500万美元是免税的。现在税法已经从400页增加到4000页，多出来的3600页是为了让富人变成超级富豪。
people now the myth around taxes is the
关于税收的一个误解是，
following that rich people don't pay
富人不缴税。
actually the sort of Rich pay a
实际上，富人缴税……
disproportionate amount of taxes so if
税收负担过重。如果
you make all of your money from current
你所有的收入都来自
income that is salary and you make a lot
工资，而且收入很高，那么
you're actually paying more taxes than
你实际上缴纳的税款比
anyone so mom's a baller she's a partner
任何人都多。比如，我妈是个富二代，她是
in a prestigious Law Firm making a
知名律师事务所的合伙人，
million bucks a year dad's a
年收入一百万美元；我爸是个
chiropractor has three people working
脊椎按摩师，有三个员工，
for him he makes 600 $1.6 million a year
年收入600万美元，加起来一共160万美元。
total ballers in order to make that kind
为了赚到这么多
of money they probably have to live in a
钱，他们可能得住在民主党占优势的
urban center in a blue state where at
州（蓝州）的城市中心，那里的税率高达
that level they're paying 45 48
45%、48%，
sometimes 52% tax rates but if dad
有时甚至52%。但如果我爸
decides to raise capital and buy a bunch
决定筹集资金，收购多家
of chiropractic clinics and they become
脊椎按摩诊所，把它们变成
Investments and he sells them for $50
投资项目，然后以5000万美元的价格卖掉，
million his tax rate plum
他的税率就会大幅下降。
so you don't want to be a super earner
所以，你不想只赚一点点钱，而是
you want to earn enough money to invest
想赚足够的钱去投资，
so you can become a super owner the top
这样你才能成为超级富豪。
25 wealthiest Americans pay about 8% in
美国最富有的25人缴纳的税款大约是8%，对吧？
tax right so actually the bottom half
实际上，收入最低的一半人
pay almost no tax they pay a lot of
几乎不用缴税，他们缴纳的
consumption taxes but it's the super
消费税很多，但真正被
earners that get screwed what I call the
坑的是那些超级富豪，也就是我所说的“超级富豪”。 那些
workhorses but once you makes the jump
辛勤工作的人，一旦你飞跃
to light speed and you own things and
到光速，拥有资产，并
you make your money from buying and
通过
selling assets your tax rate plummets
买卖资产赚钱，你的税率就会大幅下降。
there for the average person as well is
对普通人来说，真正可操作的事情
probably the the first point where you
可能就是你提到的第一点：
said a lot of what rich people do is
很多富人
they'll buy a stock so I'll I'll spend
会买股票。比如，我花1万美元买
10K on Amazon stock and then I go to a
亚马逊股票，然后去
bank and the bank give me a $5,000 loan
银行，银行给我5000美元的
against my Amazon stock taxfree and I
免税贷款，我就
just hold the Amazon stock now I've got
持有这些亚马逊股票。现在我有
5,000 taxfree if the Amazon stock goes
5000美元的免税贷款。如果亚马逊股票
to TW $20,000 in value then I can I can
涨到2万美元，我就可以
go to the bank and say it's gone up now
去银行说股票涨了，
give me another $5,000 and I just spend
再给我5000美元。然后我就可以用
and live off that money now if the
这笔钱消费生活。如果
Amazon stock
亚马逊股票
collapses I'm fine because the loan was
暴跌，我也没事，因为贷款是用
against the stock so they'll sell the
股票作抵押的，所以他们会在股价暴跌的时候卖掉股票收回投资。当然，
I mean you don't want to get into too
你肯定不想惹上
much trouble but it leverages how smart
太多麻烦，但这确实体现了聪明
people go broke but the idea is that one
人的运作方式。 破产？但关键在于，
of the great tax schemes in history is
历史上最伟大的避税方案之一就是
that stocks grow think of yourself as a
股票增值。把自己想象成一只
stock you you go up in value a million
股票，价值每年上涨一百万
bucks a year you're making a million
美元。假设你
dollars a year doing a very successful
每年都通过一个非常成功的
podcast every year the government in the
播客节目赚一百万美元，英国政府
UK is going to take 40 cents of that 40%
会从中抽取40美分。
of it if you own a million dollars in
如果你拥有价值一百万美元的
stock and it goes to two million you
股票，它涨到了两百万美元，那么在
don't get taxed on it till you sell it
你卖掉它之前，你都不需要缴税。
yeah so just never sell it never sell it
所以，永远不要卖掉它，永远不要卖掉。
and that's what elon's doing with his
这就是埃隆·马斯克用他的
companies people say he's got you know
公司做的。人们说他有两千亿
$200 billion whatever in fact he's
美元，但实际上，他是用
borrowing taxfree against those
这些公司进行免税贷款。
companies and then when he finally needs
然后，当他最终需要
to sell it to pay off some of those
出售股票来偿还部分
loans he moves to Taxas despite the fact
贷款时，他就可以把钱转移到美国。尽管
he built all his wealth in
他所有的财富都是在
California smart I think one of the
加州积累的，这很聪明。我认为
Great advant ages of life is um as it
人生的一大优势在于，就
relates to wealth creation is really
财富创造而言，
getting good tax advice because I've sat
获得良好的税务建议至关重要。因为我曾多次
here over and over again with people
与那些
that have great tax advice and some
拥有出色税务建议的人以及那些完全
people who didn't have any at all and
没有税务建议的人交流，
the outcomes are quite frankly um
结果截然不同。 坦白说，
shocking the variance and outcomes are
结果差异之大令人
quite frankly shocking from one person
震惊，一个人
going bankrupt to the other person
破产，另一个人却
becoming a multi-billionaire and it
成了亿万富翁。这
comes down to some of it comes down to
部分原因在于
their tax strategy and how they thought
他们的税务策略以及他们
about tax and have you know being around
对税务的看法。你知道，
a lot of people now that are Masters in
现在我身边有很多
tax it was like yeah describe it as
税务硕士，感觉就像
someone pulled back a curtain that I
有人拉开了我
never knew was there and all these
从未见过的帷幕，这些
people were doing magic behind this
人都在帷幕后施展魔法，
curtain and no one ever told me that
而从来没有人告诉我这帷幕的
curtain existed and it's called tax we
存在，它就叫税收。我们缴纳的
don't all pay the same tax because we're
税款并不相同，因为我们
not supposed to talk about it again not
不应该谈论它。不谈论税收
talking about it is rich people trying
是富人试图
to keep poor people down yeah because
压制穷人的原因，因为
rich people talk about their taxes all
富人总是谈论他们的税收。
the time brightest woman in my entire
我整个职业生涯中最聪明的女人名叫
Lucy Lee who is my tax Yoda who works at
露西·李，她就像我的税务尤达大师，在
a big Law Firm that I pay 1,800 bucks an
一家大型律师事务所工作，我付给她每小时1800美元，请她帮我解决税务问题。
when I set up a company I talk to my tax
当我成立公司时，我会咨询我的税务
person
顾问；
when I'm about to get a big payment from
当我即将收到
my podcast Distribution Company I talk
播客发行公司的大笔款项时，我也会
to my tax person first this is it is
先咨询我的税务顾问。 没错，一切都很重要，
everything but the key when you're young
但关键在于，年轻的时候要
is to become an owner not an earner
成为所有者，而不是赚钱的人。
you're an earner you want to bust a move
你现在是赚钱的人，你应该摆脱
out of earning and develop an army of
赚钱的束缚，建立一支
capital that goes out and kills for you
资本大军，让它在夜里为你赚钱。500
at Night 500 bucks is a lot of money
美元在你21岁的时候是一笔巨款，相当于我这个
is 10,000 when you're my age right and
年纪的1万美元，对吧？而且钱会
it's going to go really fast so just
很快花光，所以赶紧开始吧。
start and then once you become a super
一旦你成为超级
owner you have 10,000 50,000 100,000 a
所有者，拥有1万美元、5万美元、10万美元，甚至100万
million dollars in assets then then you
美元的资产，你就
can become a super tax
可以成为超级避税者。这
avoider that sounded awful that sounded
听起来很糟糕，这听起来很糟糕，这听起来很糟糕。
awful sitting here with your bucket of
坐在这里，手里拿着一桶
sand
沙子，
oh my God a bunch of mil that's right
我的天哪，一大笔钱，没错，
talking about this is how we [__] the
谈论这个，这就是我们是如何坑害
middle class St this is how we really
中产阶级的，这就是我们是如何真正
screw over the little
剥削
guy what is your Capital allocation
小人物的。你的资本配置策略是什么？
strategy how do you invest your money um
你是如何投资的？嗯，
this is you know this is the thing
你知道，这是
people want to know most about you I
人们最想知道的关于你的问题，我对此保持沉默。
keep it as painfully simple as I
我能说的就是最简单明了的，
possibly can so literally my entire net
我的全部净
worth is cash a house and index funds
资产就是现金、一套房子、指数基金，还有
and some shares of Marquel while I'm on
一些Marquel的股票（我是
the bo directors and that's it there's
董事会成员），仅此而已，没有其他任何东西了。
nothing else my entire I can summarize
我的所有资产都可以
everything so easily and so cleanly and
如此轻松、如此清晰地概括，真的就这些。
truly that's it and it's not even like I
而且我甚至
have 20 bank accounts I I have one bank
没有20个银行账户，我只有一个银行
account one brokerage account like in a
账户，一个证券账户，就像
house and that's it so simple why why
房子里的资产一样，就这些。就这么简单。为什么是
into index funds outside of investing it
指数基金？因为你的资本配置策略几乎和我的一模一样。我也想谈谈房子的事，但是，读了你的书之后，我就不再尝试选股了，除了投资
in starting companies so I'm a
初创公司之外，我把所有可用的资金都投资到了指数基金里。我持有大概
shareholder in I don't know 50 60 70
50、60、70
companies I all my other available
家公司的股份，我所有其他可用的
capital is invested in index funds and
资金都投资到了指数基金里。
then I have a very long-standing large
此外，我还长期持有大量以太坊，大概有
like six years or something yeah which
六年左右了，收益
has done me very well yeah that is it
非常好。就是这样。
based on the fact that I run a software
我投资以太坊的另一个原因是…… 我经营一家基于
business that is in blockchain and I
区块链的软件公司，我
could see that developers are building
发现开发者们在
on top of ethereum more than any other
以太坊上开发的次数比其他任何
blockchain so that Insight was really
区块链都多，所以Insight
beneficial to me and six years so even
对我真的很有帮助。六年过去了，即使
with the big fall of the last two years
过去两年市场大幅下跌，
you're still up a lot yeah I I think
你的收益仍然很高。是的，我觉得
your book taught me that successful
你的书教会了我，成功的
investing is when you lose the password
投资就是当你忘记了
to your investment account yes that's
投资账户的密码。没错，就是这样。
exactly it I don't actually think you
我其实不认为你
said that in there but that's like when
在书中明确说过这一点，但就像
I lose the password to my investment
我忘记了投资
account I'm so proud of myself because
账户密码一样，我为自己感到骄傲，因为
it means I haven't checked it in
这意味着我已经很久没查看过账户了。
forever and so it was funny cuz you were
所以这很有趣，因为你
coming today I thought oh yeah well I
今天要来，我想，哦，是的，我把
have all this money in these index funds
钱都投到这些指数基金里了，
I'll check it and I thought [__] I don't
我去看看。然后我想，糟糕，我不
know the password I good that's why
知道密码。太好了，这就是为什么
you're going to do okay the reason I do
你会做得这么好。我这样做的原因很
this what's important is that I am not
重要，因为我不是那种
one of the people who says nobody can
认为没有人能
beat the market so therefore use index
战胜市场，所以就应该使用指数
funds that's not what I believe I think
基金的人。我不这么认为。
there I think it's extremely hard to
我认为
beat the market and very few people will
战胜市场极其困难，很少有人能
do it but I think there are really smart
做到，但我认为…… 真正聪明的
people who can do it and people who I
人，以及我
know who I could invest with the reason
认识的可以一起投资的人，
I don't is not because I don't believe
我之所以不这么做，并非因为我不相信
it can be done it's because the variable
它能做到，而是因为我投资
that I want to maximize for in my
中想要最大化的变量
investments is endurance if I can just
是持久性。如果我能在一段时间内
earn average returns for an above
获得高于平均水平的平均回报，就能取得足以
literally put you in the top 5% of
跻身前5%
investors my parents are a great example
投资者行列的成功。我的父母就是一个很好的例子。他们很
of this my parents are smart people but
聪明，但
they really they have no Financial
实际上没有任何金融
background and they have like minimal
背景，对
financial interest I would say and but
金融的兴趣也微乎其微。然而，他们已经坚持用
they have dollar cost average into index
美元成本平均法投资指数
funds for going on 40 years now and
基金近40年了。
literally if you look at their returns
如果你看看他们的收益，就会发现
they've never sold anything ever and
他们从未卖出过任何投资
literally if you look at the returns
标的。如果你看看他们的收益，
they'd probably be in the top 3% of
他们很可能跻身专业投资者的前3%。对于
anyone that doesn't know what is dollar
不了解美元
cost averaging and what is an index fund
成本平均法和指数基金的人来说，
dollar cost averaging means you buy the
美元成本平均法意味着你每个月都购买
same dollar amount of Investments every
相同金额的投资，无论
doesn't matter what the stock market's
市场行情如何，经济衰退、繁荣还是萧条，都保持不变。
the stock market on the first of every
每个月的第一天，股市里都会自动扣除100美元（或其他金额）。
month now most people who like have a
现在，大多数拥有
401k at work are doing this whether they
401k退休金计划的人，无论他们是否
know it or not they have $100 or
意识到，都在不知不觉中这样做。他们
whatever removed from every paycheck and
每张工资单上都会自动扣除100美元（或其他金额），这笔钱会
it goes into the funds that they own and
进入他们拥有的基金
feel in the stock market I wake up I
账户。他们无需做任何操作，无论你是否意识到，这笔钱实际上就已经在自动扣除了。与此相反的是，有些人会根据自己对股市的感受进行买卖。比如，我早上醒来，
watch CNBC I decided to sell and I'm
看了CNBC，决定卖出，等我
better about the market it's the
对市场感觉好转后再买入。
contrast to that an index fund is just a
指数基金则不同，它只是一个
single fund that owns hundreds or
持有成百上千只股票的单一基金。
thousands of stocks within it and if
如果它的投资组合
it's diverse enough if it's big enough
足够多元化，规模足够大，那么
really what you're doing is you're
你实际上就
owning a slice of the global economy
拥有了全球经济的一部分。
which is how I think about it it's
我是这样理解的：它包含
thousands of individual stocks in there
成千上万只股票，比如
Tesla Apple whatever it would be but
特斯拉、苹果等等。但
really what you're doing is you're
实际上，你
owning a slice of capitalism if I was
拥有的是资本主义的一部分。如果我是
your son and I said Dad prove to me that
你的儿子，我会说：“爸爸，证明给我看……” 对我来说，
that's a better long-term wealth
这才是
creation strategy than buying crypto or
比购买加密货币或
buying companies that I use or like how
我使用的公司更好的长期财富创造策略。或者，
would you explain that to your to your
你会如何向你的孩子解释这一点？你在
next one year or five years is going to
未来一年或五年内的表现
have no role whatsoever on your lifetime
与你一生
ability to generate wealth all that's
创造财富的能力毫无关系。
returns you can earn all that matters
重要的不是你能获得的最高回报，而是
are is what are the returns that you can
你能持续获得的最高回报。
all that matters is your endurance it
重要的是你的毅力。
doesn't matter if you can double your
你今年能否让你的钱翻倍，甚至
money again the next year all that
明年能否再翻倍，都无关紧要。
matters is can you stick and keep it
重要的是你能否
going for 50 years that's where
坚持50年。这就是复利的由来。
compounding comes from prove it all
证明这一切吧，
because the formula for compounding is
因为复利的公式是
returns to the power of time that's not
回报与时间的幂次方。虽然不完全是
quite it but like more or less that's it
这样，但大致就是这样。
so in that equation if you understand
在这个等式中，如果你理解了
the math all of the heavy lifting comes
数学，所有繁重的工作都
from the exponent give me a case study
来自指数。给我一个案例，说明
where someone has followed that strategy
有人运用这种策略
and done well okay here's one way to
并取得了成功。好的，
explain it that I use in the book 99% of
我在书中用一种方式解释：沃伦·巴菲特99%的
Warren buffets net worth was accumulated
净资产是…… 巴菲特
birthday after he turned 60 years old
60岁之后积累的
99% of his wealth Jesus has been
财富占他总财富的99%。
accumulated after that period because
因为
the longer you hold that four the
持有时间越长，
crazier the numbers get when he was 60 I
财富增长就越惊人。他60岁时身价大约
think he was worth about $3 billion lot
30亿美元，
of money he's a multi-billionaire but
是亿万富翁。
now that he's 90 he's worth over hundred
如今他90岁了，身价超过千亿美元，
billion and he's given like a 100
并且捐出了1000
billion away to charity so if he didn't
亿美元用于慈善事业。如果他没有捐钱，
do that he'd be worth he'd go from 3
他的身价会从30亿美元飙升
billion to 200 billion since he's been
到2000亿美元，因为他
60 cuz the numbers just get crazier at
60岁时的财富增长速度惊人。如果
his if his Market if his net worth goes
股市
up 10% in one year he makes1 billion
一年上涨10%，他的净资产就能增长10亿美元，是他
when he was 60 so that's when you look
60岁时的三倍。所以，当你
at somebody like Buffett is he a great
审视像巴菲特这样的人时，你会发现，他是一位伟大的
investor is he a great stock picker of
投资者，一位优秀的选股者，
course but the real secret to his
当然，但他成功的真正秘诀
success is that he's been a good
在于，他
investor for 80 years and if he had
80年来一直是一位优秀的投资者。 如果他
retired at age 60 or at age 50 nobody
60岁或50岁就退休，恐怕没人会
would have ever heard of him he would
知道他。他会像其他
multi-billionaires who lives in Florida
住在佛罗里达、
and plays golf and like you've never
打打高尔夫的亿万富翁一样，默默无闻。他之所以
heard of him the reason he use a
家喻户晓，
household name is because he's been
是因为他从
he's been 11 years old and he's never
11岁起就一直坚持投资，从未
stopped it's just the endurance that's
间断。让
made him so wealthy not necessarily the
他如此富有的并非
annual returns patience it's a difficult
年回报率，而是他的毅力。耐心是一种很难得的
thing it also reminds me of the story
品质。这让我想起了
that you talk about in the introduction
你在书的引言中提到的
of your book about the janitor Ronald
清洁工罗纳德·
James Reed yeah who when he died in 2014
詹姆斯·里德的故事。他于2014年去世，
age 92 had a net worth of over 8
享年92岁，净资产超过800
million and he was a janitor how did he
万美元。他只是个清洁工。他是怎么
do that he took what very little money
做到的？他把
mopping floors at the gas station he put
在加油站做清洁工时攒下的微薄积蓄都投入
it in stocks and he left it alone for 70
了股票，然后70
years and that's it that's all you need
年不碰。就是这样。这就是
that's all you need to do if you have
你所需要的全部。 如果你
endurance in your investing and you can
在投资方面有毅力，并且能够
keep it going for years or decades you
坚持数年甚至数十年，你就
don't need to be a genius stock picker
不需要成为选股天才。
and not only do you not need to do it if
不仅如此，如果
you have endurance you're going to beat
你有毅力，你就能战胜
literally 97 or 99% of the genius stock
97%甚至99%的所谓“天才”
Pickers and what's so interesting about
选股者。有趣的是，
it is like picking the right stocks is
选对股票很难，本来就应该很难。
there's no world in which everybody who
世界上没有哪个地方所有
tries to beat the market is going to do
试图战胜市场的人都能成功，这当然
it of course it's hard just like being
很难，就像成为
an NBA player is hard and but having
一名NBA球员一样难。但
endurance is like largely in your
毅力很大程度上取决于你自己。
control it's so much easier to just be
保持
patient than it is to pick the right
耐心远比
stocks every single day now I think some
每天都去选对股票容易得多。我认为有些
people nature nurture some people like
人天生就具备这种能力，有些人后天培养，比如
probably Ronald Reed and my parents just
罗纳德·里德和我的父母，他们天生就
understand it naturally it's not hard
懂得
for them to be patient but do like there
耐心，对他们来说并不难。但有些
are professional investors who work 80
职业投资者每周工作80个
hours a week for 30 years to try to beat
小时，持续30年，试图战胜
the market and they can't do it not only
市场，但他们做不到。这
some that that explains like most of
解释了为什么大多数
them and even the ones who can do it are
人，甚至包括那些…… 能做到的人
maybe going to beat the market by half a
或许每年能跑赢市场0.5%或
percent per year one% per year but if
1%，但如果
you can have endurance that is that's a
你能坚持下去，那
bigger benefit than you can have by even
收益将远超那些
being like a very successful stock
非常成功的
picker like somebody who outperforms the
选股者，比如那些
market by one percentage Point per year
每年跑赢市场1个百分点，
and they can do that for 10 years that's
并且能连续10年都做到这一点的人。这很
amazing that's like Mount Rushmore
了不起，就像拉什莫尔山上的
investor but somebody who earns average
投资大师。但一个收益平平的人，如果能坚持
returns and doesn't for 20 years is
20年，积累的
going to have way more money you do it
财富也会比你多得多。如果你能坚持
for 30 years you're going to be Filthy
30年，你就会成为
Rich You' be like Ronald Reed you can be
亿万富翁，像罗纳德·里德那样。你可以是
a janitor who leaves eight million to
一个清洁工，死后留下800万美元给
charity when you die is buying a house a
慈善机构。买房究竟是
good or bad financial decision my
好是坏的财务决定？我
brother who works in my company and he's
哥哥在我公司工作，很多年前他向
the one that introduced me to your book
我推荐了你的书。他
many many years ago said to me something
跟我说过类似这样的话：“
along the lines of Steve don't buy
史蒂夫，别为了
houses to make money because you have
赚钱而买房，因为你有
the ability to play a different set of
能力玩一套
games that very few people can play yeah
很少有人能玩的游戏。”
and what I mean by that is he kind of
我的意思是，他
explained it to me go listen everyone
跟我解释过，每个人
can buy a house so returns there aren't
都能买房，所以…… 投资回报不会
going to be huge go find a game that
很高，去找个
like only you can play you'll get bigger
只有你能玩的游戏，收益会更高。
returns if you're buying a house because
如果你买房是因为
you think it's going to be a good
你觉得这是一项不错的
Financial investment stop like even if
投资，那就别想了。就算
it turns out in hindsight that it was it
事后证明确实如此，也
doesn't matter I think these are just
无济于事。我认为这纯粹是
purely lifestyle decisions and I think
生活方式的选择。
so many people get screwed up when
很多人在
they're in a spot in their life where
人生中本该
they should be renting because they need
租房的时候却犯了错，因为他们需要
to be mobile they need to move around to
流动性，需要搬家去
a new job new career new school whatever
新的工作、新的事业、新的学校等等。
it is but they end up buying because
但他们最终还是买了房，因为
they think they're going to make money
他们觉得买房能赚钱，这就是
problem so I own a house
问题所在。我拥有一套房子，
and if I ended up losing money on it I I
如果最终亏了钱，我也
I don't think I'd care that that's not
不会在意。
why I'm owning it I'm owning it just
我买房不是为了赚钱，只是为了
because I want the stability for my
给
family people people buy houses because
家人带来稳定。人们买房是因为
they think that they're making loads of
他们认为能从中赚很多
money from because there have been
钱，因为历史上确实出现过
periods in time in which people have
人们靠买房
made loads of money historically like
赚很多钱的时期，但这只是
that's the anomaly historically in the
历史上的例外情况。 经
for inflation go nowhere it's just been
通胀调整后，美国和英国的房价其实并没有上涨，只是在
the last 20 or 30 years that there's
过去二三十年里，出现了一个
this very brief window of time that
短暂的窗口期，人们认为
owning a house was a great investment
拥有房产是一项极好的投资。
Robert Schiller won the Nobel Prize
罗伯特·席勒
about a decade ago for is work in
大约十年前因其研究而获得诺贝尔奖，他的研究
showing that over the last 150 years in
表明，过去150年里，经
the United States adjusted for inflation
通胀调整后，美国
most home prices have been flat as a
大部分地区的房价几乎纹丝不动，
pancake it's just the last 20 years that
只是近20年的房价上涨推高了
have inflated people's expectations of
人们对房产收益的预期。从
do statistically there's going to be at
统计学角度来看，
least one person listening to this that
至少有一位听众此刻正在出价购买
house under the assumption that it's
房产，并认为这
going to help them stack
能帮助他们积累
wealth if they were purely doing it for
财富。如果他们纯粹出于这个
those reasons what would you tell them
原因，你会建议他们怎么
do instead if that's purely the reason
做？如果这真的是他们的唯一理由，那就赶紧逃命吧，千万别
run for run for your life don't do it
这么做。
particularly I mean it it used to be and
我的意思是，过去确实如此，
maybe it still is like this in many
也许现在在
cities in America in the UK but it used
美国和英国的许多城市仍然如此，但
to be that rentals were almost without
过去出租房几乎都是
exception shitty houses there were no
破烂不堪的房子，根本没有
good rentals a big change at least in
好的出租房。至少在
America in the last 20 years is that
美国，这种情况在过去发生了很大的变化。  20年来，
most big cities have tons and tons of
大多数大城市都有大量的
luxury apartments to live in and that
豪华公寓可供居住，这些公寓
are great places to live and they're in
位于
the city centers and they got beautiful
市中心，拥有漂亮的
granite countertops and they're great
花岗岩台面，是绝佳的居住
places to live don't fall for the idea
地。不要被“租房就
that you can't live well if you're
不能过上好日子”这种想法蒙蔽，
renting I think that's that's that's the
我认为这才是
problem and realize that if you're doing
问题所在。要知道，如果你是
it for financial reasons you're probably
为了经济原因而租房，你很可能要为
an investment that historically has been
一项历史上
a very bad investment like if you put it
非常糟糕的投资借一大笔钱。比如说，你到底在干什么？你要
of thousands of dollars for an
为一项
investment that historically has been a
历史上
loss that's what you're doing here does
亏损的投资借几十万美元，这就是你现在做的。
you feel good about that that's what I'd
你觉得这样好吗？这就是我想
say to that person
对那些人说的话。
speed I I would love to be in the room
我真想亲眼看看，当
somewhere where that person has just
那个人
looked at their partner after persuading
说服他的伴侣
them to make that offer because it was
做出那个承诺后，他看着对方的表情，因为那会让
going to make them Rich sorry
他一夜暴富。抱歉
guys so to make sure I I and everyone
各位，为了确保我和所有
listening understands what what the
听众都明白什么是
blockchain is it's this public can think
区块链，它是一个公共的…… 把它想象成一个
of it as this database in the sky and
位于天空中的数据库，
everybody who has their computer on and
所有拥有自己能力的人都会查看这个数据库。 计算机开机并
is interacting with the dat datase in
与空中的数据库交互，
the sky so you no longer need a
因此你不再需要
government or a bank checking the
政府或银行来检查
in the database in the sky because now
空中数据库中的交易和合同，因为现在
all of our computers that are on
所有
interacting with it are in the
与它交互的计算机都在
background checking that if I send you
后台进行检查：如果我给你发送
one Bitcoin if I do something on this
一个比特币，或者我
database in the sky it
在空中的数据库中进行任何操作，它都
is um in accordance with the history of
符合数据库的历史记录，
the database and um it is in line with
并且与数据库保持一致。简单来说，它
it less complicated it just makes it a
使之成为一个
source of Truth okay in a world where we
真理来源。在一个我们
don't even know who is who online who
甚至不知道谁是谁、谁
owes each other what any of these
互相欠债的世界里，
things we now have source of truth that
我们现在拥有一个每个人
everybody can agree on and everyone can
都能认同、
see and everybody can see and you don't
每个人都能看到的真理来源，你不需要
need to trust anybody and so that as a
信任任何人。因此，这项
technology solves many things problems
技术解决了许多
that we don't even know we've got
我们甚至不知道自己存在的问题，
because they're so part of
因为它们是我们
exist so the technology is not about
生存方式的一部分。所以这项技术与金钱无关，它
about
关乎
truth
真理、价值
and exchanging value and creating value
交换和
in a digital age now what is interesting
在数字时代创造价值。
and Powerful about this
这项技术有趣且强大的地方在于，
technology is we've seen Technologies
我们在互联网出现
similar before the
之前就已经见过类似的技术。
internet we've seen Broadband we've seen
我们见证了宽带的发展，见证了
these big global infrastructure
这些大型全球基础设施的建设。其中
things most of those the internet was a
大部分，比如互联网，都是
public service
公共服务，而
good Broadband was all built private
宽带则完全由私营
sector we didn't get to make money out
部门建设。我们并没有真正从中获利，
of these things really Amazon made the
亚马逊或
money or or whoever it was building the
其他建设
Broadband they all went bust as well
宽带的公司赚了钱，但他们最终也都破产了。而
what we've got here is this very clever
我们现在看到的，是一个非常巧妙的
thing that everybody in this Block Chain
机制：区块链中的每个人都会因其
play in maintaining the blockchain in
在
maintaining the blockchain and because
维护区块链中所扮演的角色而获得奖励。由于
these things are scarce and let's say
这些资源是稀缺的，
Bitcoin being the most classic example
比如最经典的比特币，其总量
there's only 21 million that will ever
只有2100万枚，
that is a reward system so the people
因此，我们创造了一种稀缺资产奖励机制。
who mine the Bitcoin they use the
挖矿的人，他们消耗
electricity to solve the algorithm to
电力来解决算法问题，从而
get the Bitcoins to make sure there's
获得比特币，确保其总量
only 21 million well they get rewarded
只有2100万枚，他们会获得奖励。
the people who verify the chain get
验证区块链的人也会获得奖励。
remed and then we can buy the asset
然后，我们可以购买这些资产，这
which is actually us
实际上是
investing in the future use cases of
对未来应用场景的投资。
this thing are people going to use it
人们会用它
for storing wealth or building stuff so
来存储财富或建造东西。
now you get this Global infrastructure
现在，我们拥有了一个全球基础设施
layer of which people can invest now
层，人们可以对其进行投资。现在，
let's go back to the example of
让我们回到人工智能的例子。
ai 99 % of people listening to this will
99%的听众
not be able to invest in it apart from
除了
buying some of those big public
购买一些大型上市
companies because they're not accredited
公司的股票外，都无法投资区块链，因为他们不是合格
investors they're not allowed they don't
投资者，他们没有资格投资，他们看不到
get to see it an Insider all of this
内幕消息等等。区块链则恰恰相反，
inverse it is
它是分数形式的。
fractional so a Bitcoin you don't have
所以，你不必以今天6万美元的价格购买一个比特币，
today you can buy
你可以购买它的
fraction so remember we talked about
分数。还记得我们之前讨论过的
property and the guys who own the big
房地产吗？那些拥有
highend property make all the
高端房产的人赚得盆满钵满，
money none of us can buy the $50 million
我们这些普通人根本买不起曼哈顿价值5000万美元的
apartment in Manhattan and then do it up
公寓，然后装修一番再以
and flip it for 250
2.5
million now
亿美元的价格卖掉。现在有了
blockchain we can all put 10% of our
区块链，我们都可以把工资的10%投入
paycheck in it do you think people
其中。你觉得人们
should yeah and more but the point being
应该这样做吗？当然应该，甚至更多。但重点
is this is the only globally homogeneous
是，这是地球上唯一全球统一的
asset on Earth it's the same in Nigeria
资产。它在尼日利亚、
as it is in Brazil as it is in London as
巴西、伦敦、
it is in Silicon Valley as it is in
硅谷、
India as it is in Pap
印度、
Guinea and everybody is on an equal
巴布亚新几内亚都是一样的，每个人都站在同一
footing you can put the same percentage
起跑线上，你可以投入相同比例的资产。
of your worth in it okay that is
这真是令人
mind-blowing and it bypasses the banking
难以置信，而且它绕过了银行体系。
system The Brokerage system and all the
经纪系统以及所有
other incumbent things that get in the
其他阻碍
way of a Nigerian buying an
尼日利亚人购买
International
国际
Investment so we've got a playing field
投资的现有因素，使得我们拥有一个公平的竞争环境，让所有人都能参与到有史以来
that's leveled in the fastest growing
增长最快的
technology of all time in the fastest of
技术、有史以来
pretesting asset in price terms of all
价格预测试速度最快的资产、最短时间内面向
is globally available to
全球
anybody and then you realize holy [__]
所有人开放的项目中。然后你会意识到，我的天哪，
okay this is important now why that's
这太重要了！为什么这很重要？
because having more investors in it
因为投资者越多，它的
means the it becomes more valuable which
价值就越高，这
means you're more likely to secure it
意味着你更有可能获得它。
people want to join the network to earn
人们想要加入网络来赚取
some of these tokens to secure it the
这些代币来获得保障，基于此
more use cases get built upon it because
构建的应用案例也会越来越多，因为
people are making money and it
人们正在赚钱，它利用
bootstraps it's behavioral economics
行为经济学原理，通过
it's an incentive based system to
激励机制来
bootstrap the most ridiculous startup
启动有史以来最荒谬的创业
idea of all time which is I'm going to
想法——我要
entirely disrupt money and create a new
彻底颠覆金融体系，创建一个新的
internet I mean that's laughably stupid
互联网。我的意思是，这简直愚蠢至极，
and that's what's happening one of the I
但这正是正在发生的事情。我
run a company called um third which is a
运营一家名为“Um Third”的公司，这是一家
web three infrastructure business we
Web 3基础设施公司。
we've raised quite a lot of money for
我们已经为公司筹集了相当多的资金，
the company about $30 million now and we
大约3000万美元。我们
have a big team and it's interesting for
拥有…… 团队规模庞大，
me to observe the use cases because
观察这些应用案例对我来说很有意思，因为
people come to third web to build on the
人们来到 Third Web 就是为了在
blockchain and one of the really
区块链上进行开发。在过去的 12 个月里，
interesting use cases we've seen over
我们看到了一个非常有趣的案例，而且发展迅猛，那就是
exploded is is gaming people
游戏开发。人们正在
building uh web 3 blockchainbased games
开发基于 Web 3 区块链的游戏。
because if you think about games like
想想 FIFA 这样的游戏，它在
UK where we're big soccer fans or other
英国非常火爆，因为我们都是足球迷。或者
games like you know um RuneScape back in
像以前的 RuneScape 这样的游戏，
game in FIFA you have a messy card in
游戏里都有资产。在 FIFA 里，你可能有一张杂乱的卡片；在
RuneScape you might have a sword the
RuneScape 里，你可能有一把剑。
thing that the blockchain now enables us
区块链现在让我们能够将
to do is to take those assets from the
这些游戏资产带到
game so I can if the if the sword was on
游戏外进行交易。也就是说，如果一把剑在
the ethereum blockchain even though I'm
以太坊区块链上，即使我
not inside the game I can trade that
不在游戏里，我也可以
sword on the ethereum blockchain and so
在以太坊区块链上交易这把剑。因此，
we've seen at third web is people
我们在 Third Web 看到的最杰出的应用案例之一就是人们
building AI games sorry people building
开发 AI 游戏，哦不，是开发
web 3 games because these assets are now
Web 3 游戏。因为这些资产现在
valuable it's great for the game
很有价值，这对游戏
developer they've now got this brand new
开发者来说非常棒。 对他们公司来说，这是一种全新的经济模式，对
it's great for the people that own those
那些
assets in the game because they've now
在游戏中拥有资产的人来说也是好事，因为
those assets are now more valuable
现在这些资产更有价值了，
because more people can access them and
更多的人可以访问它们。
if if I own ethereum yeah if I own an
如果我拥有以太坊，没错，
ethereum token yeah which I Do by the
我的确拥有以太坊代币，
way I've been stacking it and refusing
我一直在囤积，拒绝
to sell um but how do I benefit from the
出售。那么，我如何从
fact that games are now being built in
游戏现在用
ethereum and it's really simple if we'd
以太坊构建这一事实中获益呢？这很简单。如果我们当初都能
have all been given shares in Facebook
拿到Facebook的股份，
when it started we'd have all been
我们都会变得
hilariously rich but we didn't the VC's
非常富有，但我们没有。风险投资公司拿到了股份，然后它
market and then you have to have a
上市了。然后你必须拥有一个
brokerage account you have to be
经纪账户，你必须获得
approved right what this is happening
批准，对吧？现在的情况是，
you buy an ethereum token
你今天购买一个以太坊代币，
today if ethereum ends up becoming
如果以太坊最终发展
bigger and more uses your token value
壮大，用途更加广泛，你的代币价值就会
goes up it's as simple as that so you
上涨，就这么简单。所以，你只需
from your mobile phone and you don't
通过你的手机就能参与到一场完整的技术革命中，而且你不需要
need anybody to approve it or do
任何人批准或做
anything yes there's regulation stuff
任何事情。当然，有一些监管方面的东西，
but simple stuff like that it's pretty
但就是这么简单。 对世界上
straightforward for almost everybody in
几乎所有人来说，这都很简单明了，
the world so therefore we talked about
所以我们讨论了
how do you invest in your disruption and
如何投资颠覆性技术以及
the future of technology okay here's one
科技的未来。好的，这里有一个
where you can really do it
你可以真正做到
and it's easy to do a couple of
而且很容易操作的例子。
questions here then so you said it's
这里有几个问题。你说很
easy to do yeah let's talk
容易，是的，那我们来谈谈实际
practicalities how do does one do it I
操作。具体该怎么做呢？我
can do it on my phone I have to call
可以用手机操作，但我需要打电话给
someone how do I invest in crypto you
别人。我该如何投资加密货币？你
just open a crypto account yeah um with
只需要开一个加密货币账户就行了。是的，在
one of the big crypto provid coinbase
大型加密货币提供商 Coinbase、
Kraken crypto.com who are in a Gemini
Kraken 或 Crypto.com 上开户，它们都属于 Gemini 集团。
what about this though my bank my
不过，我的银行，我的
digital bank is offering me to buy
数字银行，也提供
crypto on there should I do that yes you
加密货币购买服务，我应该用吗？是的，你可以用，
can and you could do it bya PayPal
而且你可以通过 PayPal 进行购买。总之，要从某个地方
starts somewhere I'm not going to say no
开始，我不会说不，
but you will go down the journey that
但你会经历
everybody goes down which is the easiest
每个人都会经历的过程，最简单的
on ramp is the best revolute whatever I
入门方式就是最好的方式，比如 Revolute 之类的，我
don't care just do
不在乎，去做就对了。
it get a feel for what it's like to own
感受一下拥有这种
an asset that goes up and down a
资产的感觉，它的价格波动
lot particularly down when it goes down
很大，尤其是在下跌的时候，
it makes you feel terrible and you got
你会感觉很糟糕，你必须
to learn about how to deal with it and
学会​​如何应对。
then because it goes up over time if you
然后，因为它也会上涨。 如果你
don't do anything and you've chosen a
什么都不做，而且你选择的是一项
good quality asset that's provable as a
优质资产，这项
as an asset in itself it'll probably go
资产本身的价值是可以证明的，那么随着时间的推移，它很可能会
up over time in fact highly likely to go
升值，事实上，它很可能会
up a lot and then you'll start thinking
大幅升值。然后你可能会想，
do you remember Ral saying that the bank
你还记得拉尔说过银行
owns the stuff and I don't own it and
拥有这些东西，而我并不拥有吗？
then you might say oh but the magic here
然后你可能会说，哦，但神奇之处在于，与
is unlike the bank where I can't take
银行不同，银行最多只能取出
more than 10 grand
1万英镑，
out I can put it all on my little Ledger
我可以把所有钱都放在我的Ledger
device because what's a ledger device a
设备上。Ledger设备是什么？
ledger device is it's actually it's a
Ledger设备实际上是一家
company provides it but what it
公司提供的。但它的本质
is because this is just an address on a
是
blockchain and think of it is like your
区块链上的一个地址，你可以把它想象成你的
mailbox you can send stuff to it but you
邮箱，你可以把东西发送到那里，但你
can't actually take it
不能
out like your email somebody can't read
像你的电子邮件那样把它取出来。别人不能读取
all your emails but they can send you
你所有的邮件，但他们可以给你发送
emails well that that part that's
邮件。这部分是
private that
私密的，也就是
secure Pass Key essentially
安全的通行密钥。
well you keep that to yourself and it's
你需要自己保管好它，它
stored on a device and there's a
存储在一个设备上。这需要一些
complicated way of doing it and you'll
复杂的操作，你必须
have to go through that which is you
经历这个过程，也就是说，你
have to have this seed phrase that does
必须拥有这个设备。 助记词就是用来保护以太坊的，
it this technology will change quite
这项技术
soon you know fingerprints face prints
很快就会被指纹、面部识别
and a bunch of other stuff but basically
等等取代。但基本上，
a little USB stick will secure that you
一个小小的U盘就能确保你的资金安全，你
can go and put in the safe or go and
可以把它放在保险箱里，或者
take it to your Nan's house or whatever
带到奶奶家，或者任何你想去的地方。
it is can
它可以
secure your money that it's only yours
确保你的钱只属于你，
and nobody can take it out I have mine
没有人能拿走。
on a ledger so I have my ethereum on a
我的以太坊就存在一个Ledger设备上，
small it's kind of like a small USB
它就像一个小小的U
stick and then that USB stick is
盘，这个U盘受到大约
protected by like 24 words or whatever
24个单词的保护，没错，
it is that's right and those words are
这些单词目前被写在
on pieces of paper in different
不同国家的纸片上。
and it means that no matter what happens
这意味着无论发生什么，
no matter where I am in the world no
无论我在世界哪个角落，
matter who comes for me I can always
无论谁来找我，我都能随时
retrieve the x th000 ethereum that I
取回我
have on this Ledger device yeah um
存在这个Ledger设备上的几千个以太坊。
unlike a bank where my my account could
不像银行，我的账户可能会被
get Frozen by the government or they
政府冻结，或者他们
could empty my bank they could freeze my
可能会清空我的银行账户，冻结我的
bank I can I will always have that value
银行，但我的以太坊始终拥有这些价值。
and also you know there's a famous
你知道，美国
example of the conversation of gold in
黄金交易就是一个著名的例子。
many countries in the past the good
过去很多国家都这么做过。
thing about this magic internet money is
这种神奇的网络货币的好处在于，
you have to physically cross borders
你必须带着它实际跨越国界。
with it yeah yeah think of all the
想想那些
Jewish people who had to take money and
不得不把钱、
diamonds and gold out of Nazi Germany
钻石和黄金从纳粹德国
and out of Europe
和欧洲带出来的犹太人吧，
it was hard to do here you don't have to
这有多难。在这里，你
do anything you just need to remember a
什么都不用做，只需要记住一个
seed phrase a seed phrase being
助记词，助记词
basically a string of words yeah yeah do
基本上就是一串单词。
you know for people that are in that
你知道吗？对于那些像我一样，多年来一直处于月光族状态的人来说，
I'd get paid for my call center I'd go
我拿到呼叫中心的工资后，
and spend the money I'd pretty much
几乎会在头几天就把钱花光，然后就只能
and I was just waiting the next three
等着接下来的三个
weeks for the next
星期才能拿到下一笔
paycheck what advice would you give them
工资。你会给他们什么建议
about getting out of that cycle cuz it
来摆脱这种循环呢？因为如果你深陷其中，
because you almost feel imprisoned by
你会感觉自己几乎被困住了。在
before I give the advice I want to
我给出建议之前，我想先向他们
explain to that person what's happening
解释一下发生了什么，
because you are the Prime customer for
因为你是
our economic system Banks love you
我们经济体系的主要客户。银行喜欢你，
because they can sell you payday loans
因为他们可以向你出售发薪日贷款，
they can sell you credit cards they can
可以向你出售信用卡，他们可以…… 他们向
sell you lines of credit and they can
你推销信用额度，让
keep you in debt for the rest of your
你一辈子都背负债务，
life which means you keep making the
这意味着你不断地让
bank Rich corporations love you because
银行获利。富有的公司喜欢你，因为
when we show you this nice bag when we
当我们向你展示这款漂亮的包包，当我们向
show you this nice vacation you're going
你展示这个美好的假期时，你会毫不犹豫地
to want this stuff and so we love
想要这些东西，所以我们乐于向
selling you this stuff the government
你推销这些东西。政府也
loves you because you're going to pay
喜欢你，因为你会缴纳
the highest
最高的
taxes employees pay the highest
税款，雇员缴纳最高的
taxes and so when you're in that
税款。所以，当你处于这种
situation you are making everybody else
境地时，你是在牺牲自己的利益，让其他人变得
Rich at your
富有。
expense and so if you want to break out
因此，如果你想摆脱
of this the first thing is you got to
这种困境，首先你必须
understand you need to make yourself
明白，你必须先让自己变得
rich before you make everybody else Rich
富有，才能让其他人变得富有。
because when you're spending all your
因为当你花光所有的
money you are putting your money into
钱时，你实际上是在把钱放进别人的
their pockets and you have to stop that
口袋里，你必须停止这种行为，
you got to keep that money for yourself
你必须把钱留给自己。
you're in a boat think of it this way
想象一下，
you're in a boat and this boat has water
你身处一条船上，船舱里
just flowing in and you are sinking and
不断进水，你正在下沉，
you got to start by sealing the holes
你必须先堵住漏洞，
and that means you got to stop the
这意味着你必须停止
spending so if you are in what I call
消费。所以，如果你处于我所说的
the financial danger zone which is you
财务危险区，也就是你
don't have $2,000 saved up for an
没有2000美元的存款，那么……
if you are in that situation you are in
如果你遇到紧急情况，而且还有信用卡债务，那么你就处于
the financial danger zone and you have
财务危险区，必须
to make drastic changes that means right
做出重大改变。这意味着
now no more eating at restaurants no
现在就停止去餐馆吃饭，
more vacations no more doing anything
停止度假，停止做任何
that doesn't put money in your pocket
不能赚钱的事情，也
and no more Netflix right and the reason
停止看Netflix。
why I say this isn't because you're
我这么说并不是因为你
going to save $15 a month it's so you
每个月能省下15美元，而是为了让你
can save two hours of your time a day
每天节省两个小时的时间。
the average American is watching more
普通美国人
than 2 hours of Television a day and if
每天看电视的时间超过两个小时。如果
you don't have $2,000 saved up if you
你没有2000美元的存款，或者背负着
have credit card debt you cannot afford
信用卡债务，你就无法承受
those 2 hours a day being wasted on TV
每天浪费在电视上的这两个小时。
and that means right now you have to go
这意味着你现在必须开始
out and start using the time to learn
利用这些时间学习、
start using the time to work and start
工作，赚点外快。
so what do you do start selling stuff
那么该怎么做呢？开始卖东西，
stop spending money selling stuff you
停止花钱，卖掉你
own selling stuff you own so if you have
拥有的东西。如果你有
a TV that you're not using sell it you
一台不用的电视，就卖掉它；如果你有一辆负担
have a car that you can't afford sell it
不起的车，就卖掉它；
if you're living in a house that you
如果你住在一套负担
can't afford sell it downgrade move
不起的房子里，就卖掉它；换一套小一点的房子。
smaller and then work to earn more money
然后努力赚钱。
I've got to say the couple of things
我得说，
that I came to mind is you were saying
我脑海里浮现出几件事。你刚才也提到了这一点，说来也巧，
that and funnily enough I put myself in
我把自己代入了
the shoes of 18-year-old Steven Bartlett
18岁的史蒂文·巴特利特（Steven Bartlett）的处境。
when I was in that small apartment with
当时我和
three or four immigrants in Mosside rush
三四个移民挤在莫赛德（Mosside）那间小公寓里，匆匆忙忙地
home and I was you know my rent was
回家。你知道，我的
nothing my rent was a 1,000 150 a month
房租每月要1500美元，
which I could not afford and I could not
我根本负担不起，也
pay and I was intermittently working
付不起。我断断续续地
between call center jobs and whatever
在呼叫中心打工，挣的钱都花光了。
reason I spent it just pre is because
我花钱大手大脚的部分原因，就像
like many people watching especially men
很多观众一样，尤其是一些男人，
who sometimes feel the need because of
因为社会现状，有时会觉得有必要花钱。
the way Society is I was trying to get
我当时也想找个伴侣，这
laid at the same time and it's hard yeah
很难。是的，
when you're a young man and I say young
当你年轻的时候，这很难。我特别强调年轻
men in particular because the stats do
男人，因为统计数据确实
support the fact that there is an
支持这样一个事实：社会期望
expectation that men pay um when you're
男人花钱。当你
a young man it's particularly difficult
年轻的时候，要
to to do all of these things to cut back
做到所有这些事情，比如减少开支，
and also get laid and what am I going to
还要找个伴侣，这尤其困难。难道我要
do defer getting laid for 10 years when
推迟十年才开始找伴侣吗？
I say laid I'm really saying meeting
我说“安定下来”的真正意思是，遇到
someone and falling in love and having a
某个人，坠入爱河，拥有自己的
having a life so what do I if I if I'm
生活。那么，如果我像
living in a shoe box which I was I can't
以前那样住在鞋盒里，我该怎么办？我没法
bring anyone back there I can't take
带任何人回家，没法请
anyone for dinner I can't take anyone to
任何人吃饭，没法请任何人去看
the movies what do I do and this is why
电影。我该怎么办？这就是为什么
every Indian parents tell their kids to
每个印度父母都让孩子当
become a doctor so their son can get
医生，这样他们的儿子才能
married it's the same concept but here's
结婚。道理是一样的。但关键在于，
the thing you have to pick your hard
你必须做出选择。
either life's going to be hard now or
要么现在生活艰难，要么
your life and you have to pick what's
余生都将艰难。你必须选择
more important to you right now and you
对你来说现在更重要的事。你
know if we talk about balance if you
知道，如果我们谈到平衡，如果你
want to have a balance of everything
想在所有事情上都保持平衡——
where you want to find a girl and you
你想找到女朋友，你
want to make money and you want to stay
想赚钱，你想保持
healthy you are dividing your attention
健康——你就是在分散注意力。我
everywhere not saying it's impossible
不是说这不可能，
but very few people can actually do
但很少有人能同时做到
everything all at
所有事情。
once and if your number one goal is to
如果你的首要目标是
become wealthy if your number one goal
致富，如果你的首要目标
is to turn your finances around you have
是扭转你的财务状况，你就必须
to get serious about it because
认真对待，因为
where you put your attention is where
你把注意力放在哪里，
you get the results and so if you want
你就会得到什么结果。 所以，如果你想
to be in a better financial situation
改善财务状况，就
you were going to have to make
必须做出
sacrifices and it's difficult I can't
牺牲，这很难。我不能
come here and tell you it's going to be
告诉你这很
easy yeah because that's going to be me
容易，因为那样我就是在骗
lying to you I got to be honest I did
你。说实话，我的确
make a sacrifice and for me the
做出了牺牲。对我来说，我的
sacrifice was I started a business and
牺牲是创业。
frankly that meant that I didn't have
坦白说，这意味着我没有
time to be going out getting laid or
时间出去约会、
meeting people or socializing but it's
认识新朋友或参加社交活动。但
it my story arc ends with it going well
我的故事最终以事业成功告终，
care of itself many years later once it
多年后，当一切顺利时，爱情自然而然地出现了。
had gone well because I was so focused
因为我当时非常专注于
on myself and it's funny there is a bit
自己。有趣的是，
of a paradox to life that the more you
生活存在一个悖论：你越
actually Focus inward the more you
关注自身，就越能吸引他人。
become a magnet yeah um and the more I
而我越
focused outward the more I pursued and
关注外部世界，越是追求和
chased and sort of neglected myself the
追逐，越是忽略自己，就
the more harder it was to get people
越难
interested in me yeah and you know I I
吸引别人。你知道，我
also want to say that when I talk about
还想说，当我谈到
Building Wealth I'm not talking about
积累财富时，我指的不是贪婪，而是
coming money hungry just money greedy
贪得无厌。贪婪的
this is evil person that just cares
人是邪恶的，他们只关心
about money that's not what I'm talking
金钱。 我之所以这么说，是
about because I want you to live a
因为我希望你们能过上一种
holistic life because money is just one
整体的生活，因为金钱只是
part of your life but the second part to
生活的一部分。但另一方面，
that is I'm not telling you to never
我并不是说你们永远不要
enjoy life I'm telling you to make a
享受生活，而是说你们要在
sacrifice for a period of your life that
人生的某个阶段做出牺牲，这样
way you can enjoy the rest of your life
你们才能享受余生，再也
and never have to worry about money
不用为钱发愁。
again it's hard for us to naturally see
我们很难自然而然地把
life for Seasons especially when we're
人生分成不同的阶段，尤其是在展望未来的时候。但当我们
looking forward when we're looking back
回顾过去时，
it's very easy to say oh that was that
很容易说“哦，那是那个
season like I can sit here now and say
阶段”。比如我现在可以坐在这里说，
all that 20 to 25 was that sacrifice
20到25岁是我牺牲
everything in my life to make myself
一切去成就自己的
something season and then 25 to 30 was
阶段，而25到30岁则是在
like building and learning and then I I
积累和学习。
now you know can can think of it's
现在，你知道，我已经经历过一些阶段，所以
easier actually now to think forward in
现在更容易用阶段来思考未来。
Seasons but for someone that's hasn't
但对于那些没有经历过
been through seasons in life it's hard
人生阶段的人来说，很难用这种
to think about life in those terms I now
方式来思考人生。我现在
think of my life in these fiveyear
会把我的人生分成五年一个
Seasons mhm and that helps me to say to
阶段来思考，嗯，这有助于我
you even have conversation with my
和
partner where I go this is the season
伴侣交流。 我现在所处的阶段，
um and it will last probably roughly
嗯，大概会持续这么
this this long and I'm going to
久，在这个阶段，我会
sacrifice these things and prioritize
牺牲一些东西，优先考虑
these things in this season mhm but um
这些东西。嗯，但是，嗯，
it's hard for people to understand this
人们很难理解这个
idea it's difficult and that sacrifice
想法，这很难，做出牺牲
is difficult especially during a time
很难，尤其是在
where everybody's showing off everything
每个人都
on Instagram you look at your friends
在Instagram上炫耀一切的时代。你看着你的朋友，他们
who have a crappy job but they're
工作很糟糕，却
driving around in nicer cars going on
开着更好的车，去
better vacations going to the nicer
更好的度假胜地，去更好的
restaurants and you're thinking what did
餐厅，你会想，
I do wrong and then especially if you're
我做错了什么？特别是如果你是
a guy you have a girlfriend you have a
个男人，你有女朋友，你有
wife she's going to say how come they
妻子，她会问，为什么他们
keep get to go can they keep getting to
总是能去，为什么他们总是能
go to Cancun they keep going to these
去坎昆，为什么他们总是能去那些
nice restaurants how come you can't take
好餐厅​​，为什么你不能带
me to these nice places and now you feel
我去这些好地方？现在你会觉得
like you're doing something wrong
自己做错了什么，
because where is this discrepancy the
因为这种差距在哪里？
reason why I call my show the minority
我把我的节目叫做“少数派
mindset is because I'm a big advocate of
思维”，是因为我非常提倡
not doing what the majority of people do
不要做大多数人都在做的事情。
the first time I made a million dollars
我第一次一年赚到一百万美元的时候，
in a year I was in my 20s I was was
我才20多岁。 我当时
driving a car worth
开着一辆价值
$500 it didn't have a bumper on it it
500美元的车，连保险杠都没有，车况很差。
pretty my wife sat in that car with me
我妻子和我一起坐在那辆车里，
and my employees drove better cars than
而我的员工开的车都比我的好。
so you know uh you got to be
所以你知道，你必须要有
confident and you got to work for
自信，你必须为
something bigger and you want a partner
更远大的目标而努力，你需要一个能够理解你的伴侣。这就是
my
我的
belief which is not the easy thing
信念，但这并不容易。
it's interesting because confidence is
有趣的是，自信是一种非常
such a internal thing and I just feel
内在的东西，我觉得
like I just probably just didn't have it
我当时可能就是缺乏自信，
then cuz I I think I was scared for
因为我害怕
someone to know that I was broke I was
别人知道我穷，我
so scared to know for someone to know
太害怕别人知道
that I was broke that I just didn't
我穷了，以至于我根本不
entertain romantic relationships and
考虑恋爱关系。
that is the reason why so many people
这就是为什么很多人
will go into debt to buy vacations to
会为了度假、为了
buy things to buy stuff to look rich and
买东西、为了让自己看起来很富有而负债累累。
ironically that's the thing that keeps
讽刺的是，正是这种
their life is because they're scared to
害怕显得贫穷的行为，让很多人一辈子都贫穷下去。而
look broke and now when you try to look
当你试图让自己看起来很
rich that's the thing that's actually
富有时，这实际上反而让
keeping you broke there's another
你更穷。还有另一个
element to this which is my life was
因素，那就是我的生活
pretty miserable so when you have
非常悲惨。所以，当你拥有
a relatively miserable life when you
相对…… 当
you're working in a call center as I was
你因为在呼叫中心工作而没有多少好东西时，生活就变得很悲惨，就像我一样，经常
until 11:00 at night time doing overtime
加班到晚上11点。
every overtime hour I could get then
那时候我能抽出一个小时，
because you're all so lonely you're
因为你们都太孤独了，只能
going home alone walking home cuz you
独自步行回家，因为你们
can't afford the
付不起公交车费。
bus anything that gives you a little
任何能给你们带来一点
dopamine hit gambling this is why all
多巴胺刺激的事情，比如赌博，都行。这就是为什么所有的
the gambling shops are in the areas that
赌场都开在
struggle the worst financially because
经济最困难的地区，因为
those I mean a lot of people say because
很多人都说，
those people are looking for that you
这些人都在寻找那种
know that big payday that dopamine hit
一夜暴富的感觉，那种
from a Payday um my TV in my tiny tiny
从赌博中获得的多巴胺刺激。嗯，我那间小小的单间公寓里的电视机几乎占了
little bedsit room was like half the
半
size of the wall I was making Reckless
面墙，我当时肆意挥霍，
spending decisions because I think it
因为我觉得它能给
gave me some kind of hit that I I was
我带来
missing in my life it gave me like a
生活中缺失的某种刺激，它能给我带来一种
dopamine Rush that was and there wasn't
多巴胺的快感。在那个时候，生活中很少有
many things giving me a dopamine hit at
东西能给我带来这种感觉。你
that point in my life and see here's the
看，关键在于，在
thing during that time you are making
那段时间里，你会做出
emotional decisions yes as many people
情绪化的决定，是的，就像很多人一样。用逻辑来对抗情绪
are and it's very difficult to speak
是非常困难的，
emotion but this is where now you have
但现在你必须
to be able to understand the difference
能够理解其中的区别。
because if you're listening to this and
因为如果你正在听这段话，并且
you're in that
你正处于那种
situation you have to understand that if
境地，你必须明白，如果
you want to continue being able to that
你想继续过那种
lifestyle you're going to have to make
生活，你就必须…… 今天就必须做出
some changes today otherwise you're
一些改变，否则你这辈子都
going to be stuck in this lifestyle for
摆脱不了这种生活方式，
the rest of your life and it's only
而且只会
going to get more difficult and that's
越来越难。关键在于，
the thing is if you want to become
如果你想
wealthy the first part is just your own
致富，首先要改变的就是你的
mindset it's your own discipline and
心态，是你的自律。在
until tell you can conquer that I can
你克服这一点之前，我可以
tell you everything about investing I
告诉你所有关于投资的知识，我可以告诉你应该
funds to invest in I can tell you
投资哪些ETF和指数基金，我可以告诉你有
different investment institutions out
哪些投资机构，我可以告诉
there I can tell you which stock
你应该使用哪些股票
brokerages to use I can tell you just
经纪公司，我可以告诉你只需将
invest $ 15 % of your income into this
收入的15%投资于此，
for the next 10 20 30 years and you're
持续10年、20年、30年，你就能
going to become wealthy but until you
致富。但是，在你
can get over that mindset you're never
克服这种心态之前，你永远无法
going to become wealthy because then
致富。因为在这种
what happens in that situation is when
情况下，当
you're in that state
你处于“
of I just want to look rich I just want
我只想看起来很富有，我只想获得
to have that dopamine in I just want to
多巴胺的刺激，我只想
have some nice things because I deserve
拥有一些美好的事物，因为我值得拥有，
it I work hard you know what happens
我努力工作”的状态时，你知道接下来会发生什么吗？你会成为那些一夜
all the get-rich quick schemes because
暴富骗局的受害者，因为总会
someone's going to say
有人说“
look put $1,000 into this you'll have
看看你”， 投入1000美元，你将
1010 $1,000 in the next 3 months or I'm
在未来3个月内获得1000美元，或者我会向
going to show you you can live the
你展示如何过上
laptop lifestyle you can work 5 hours a
笔记本电脑式的自由生活，每周工作5小时，
week make $10,000 a month $10,000 a week
每月赚取10000美元，每周10000美元，
you're never going to have to worry
你再也不用
about money again just buy this
为钱发愁了。只需购买这个
program and now you're a prime candidate
项目，你现在就是最佳客户，
because now you were driven by this
因为你被“
emotion of I want that I can't imagine
我想要这个”的情绪所驱使。我无法想象
if I had an extra $10,000 a month and I
如果我每月额外获得10000美元，而且我甚
don't even have to work for it because
至不用工作，那会是什么样子。因为
you can't see past it you're all you're
你看不到其他的东西，你
doing is being sold by emotion
所做的只是被情绪左右。是
it's you you're the one that's going to
你，你才是那个会陷入
get caught up in the get-rich quick
快速致富
schemes you're the one that's going to
骗局的人。是你，你会成为
make the bank Rich because you're going
银行的“富翁”，因为你会
to get stay stuck in debt corporations
深陷债务泥潭。公司
are going to love you because they can
会喜欢你，因为他们可以
keep selling you the nicest the newest
不断地向你推销最新最好的
stuff because you want to look rich you
产品，因为你想看起来很富有，你
want to show it off to your friends you
想向朋友炫耀，你
want to show it off to the
想展示自己。 把话题交给
girls and you get stuck in that cycle
女孩们，然后你就陷入了这个循环，
isn't this cool every single
是不是很酷？
conversation I have here on the D of CEO
我在“CEO日记”节目里的每一期节目，
at the very end of it you'll know I
最后都会
asked the guest to leave a question in
请嘉宾在“CEO日记”里留下一个问题。
is we've turned every single question
我们把“CEO日记”里的每一个问题都做成了
conversation cards that you can play at
对话卡片，你可以在
home so you've got every guest we've
家里玩。卡片上包含了我们所有嘉宾提出的
ever had their question and on the back
问题，扫描卡片背面的
of it if you scan that QR code you get
二维码，就能
to watch the person who answered that
看到回答
question we're finally revealing all of
问题的人。我们终于要公布所有
the questions and the people that
问题和
answered the question the brand new
回答者了！全新
version 2 updated conversation cards are
升级的第二版对话卡片
out out right now at Theon conversation
现已在Theon conversationcards.com网站发售。
cards.com they've sold out twice
它们已经两次
instantaneously so if you are interested
瞬间售罄，所以如果你想
in getting hold of some limited edition
入手一些限量版
conversation cards I really really
对话卡片，我强烈
recommend acting quickly
建议你抓紧时间。